<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE rfc [
<!ENTITY nbsp "&#160;">
<!ENTITY zwsp "&#8203;">
<!ENTITY nbhy "&#8209;">
<!ENTITY wj "&#8288;">
]>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rfc2629.xslt"?>
<?rfc toc="yes"?>
<?rfc tocompact="yes"?>
<?rfc tocdepth="4"?>
<?rfc compact="yes"?>
<?rfc subcompact="yes"?>
<?rfc sortrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc symrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc iprnotified="no"?>
<rfc xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" ipr="trust200902" category="std" consensus="true" docName="draft-ietf-calext-jscalendar-icalendar-12" obsoletes="" updates="" submissionType="IETF" xml:lang="en" tocInclude="true" symRefs="true" sortRefs="true" version="3">
  <front>
    <title abbrev="JSCalendar">JSCalendar: Converting from and to iCalendar</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-calext-jscalendar-icalendar-12"/>
    <author initials="R." surname="Stepanek" fullname="Robert Stepanek">
      <organization>Fastmail</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>PO Box 234</street>
          <street>Collins St West</street>
          <city>Melbourne</city>
          <code>VIC 8007</code>
          <country>Australia</country>
          <region/>
        </postal>
        <email>rsto@fastmailteam.com</email>
        <uri>https://www.fastmail.com</uri>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2025" month="April" day="17"/>
    <area>Applications</area>
    <workgroup>Calendaring extensions</workgroup>
    <keyword>JSON</keyword>
    <keyword>iCalendar</keyword>
    <keyword>JSCalendar</keyword>
    <keyword>calendar</keyword>
    <keyword>events</keyword>
    <keyword>date</keyword>
    <keyword>time</keyword>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document defines how to convert calendaring information between the JSCalendar and iCalendar data formats. It considers every JSCalendar and iCalendar element registered at IANA at the time of publication. It defines conversion rules for all elements that are common to both formats, as well as how convert arbitrary or unknown JSCalendar and iCalendar elements.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <middle>
    <section>
      <name>Introduction</name>
      <section anchor="notational-conventions" numbered="true" toc="default">
        <name>Notational Conventions</name>
        <t>The key words "<bcp14>MUST</bcp14>", "<bcp14>MUST NOT</bcp14>", "<bcp14>REQUIRED</bcp14>", "<bcp14>SHALL</bcp14>", "<bcp14>SHALL NOT</bcp14>", "<bcp14>SHOULD</bcp14>", "<bcp14>SHOULD NOT</bcp14>", "<bcp14>RECOMMENDED</bcp14>", "<bcp14>NOT RECOMMENDED</bcp14>", "<bcp14>MAY</bcp14>", and "<bcp14>OPTIONAL</bcp14>" in this document are to be interpreted as described in BCP 14 <xref target="RFC2119" format="default" sectionFormat="of" derivedContent="RFC2119"/>
          <xref target="RFC8174" format="default" sectionFormat="of" derivedContent="RFC8174"/> when, and only when, they appear in all capitals, as shown here.</t>
        <t>The ABNF definitions in this document use the notations of <xref target="RFC5234"/>. ABNF rules not defined in this document either are defined in <xref target="RFC5234"/> or <xref target="RFC5545"/>.</t>
      </section>
      <section anchor="scope-and-goals">
        <name>Scope and Goals</name>
        <t>This document outlines how to convert calendaring information between the iCalendar and JSCalendar data formats.  It describes which elements are common to both, but also highlights where the two formats differ. For each common element, it defines a conversion rule and includes an example of how to convert that element. All iCalendar and JSCalendar elements currently registered at IANA are in scope, but not all of these elements are common to both formats.</t>
        <t>For elements that have no counterpart in the other format, it is the goal of this document to define how to preserve them during conversion, but in general it is not the goal to achieve this by defining new standard elements. Instead, this document defines special-purpose properties to preserve arbitrary elements. These conversion-specific properties are defined in Section <xref target="ical-prop-jsprop" format="counter"/> for iCalendar, and Sections <xref target="jscal-prop-icalcomponent" format="counter"/> and <xref target="jscal-prop-icalproperty" format="counter"/> for JSCalendar. <xref target="appendix-discrepancies"/> further outlines the discrepancies between the two formats.</t>
      </section>
      <section>
        <name>How to Read the Examples</name>
        <t>Later sections contain examples that illustrate how to convert between the iCalendar and JSCalendar data formats.  The notation of these examples is such that their main points should be clear to the reader, but their contents can also be parsed for automated testing. The following sections define the notation for such examples.</t>
        <section anchor="notation-icalendar">
          <name>iCalendar Examples</name>
          <t>An iCalendar example contains either an extract or a complete representation of iCalendar data.  It always represents an iCalendar object, even if the example only depicts non-VCALENDAR components or properties. The following rules apply:</t>
          <ul>
            <li>An example that only contains iCalendar properties implicitly represents a VEVENT component that is part of a VCALENDAR component.</li>
            <li>An example that only contains one or more non-VCALENDAR components implicitly represents a VCALENDAR component that contains them.</li>
            <li>An example that only contains a VCALENDAR component but no contained components implicitly represents a VCALENDAR component that contains a VEVENT component.</li>
            <li>Implicit components (those without a BEGIN and END, or omitted completely) are assumed to contain all mandatory properties with some value, but the actual value is irrelevant for the example.</li>
          </ul>
          <t><xref target="example-notation-icalendar-implicit-explicit"/> contains three examples, all of which represent the same iCalendar data.  In the first example, both the VEVENT component and VCALENDAR component are implicit.  In the second example, only the VCALENDAR component and its mandatory properties are implicit.  The third example depicts a complete VCALENDAR component, nothing is implicit.</t>
          <figure anchor="example-notation-icalendar-implicit-explicit">
            <name>Examples for implicit and explicit iCalendar component notation</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
SUMMARY:hello
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
DTSTAMP:20060102T030405Z
DTSTART:20060102T030405Z
SUMMARY:hello
UID:CC0A494A-6E07-4827-8294-0752DD1ECFA4
END:VEVENT
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VCALENDAR
PRODID:-//FOO//bar//EN
VERSION:2.0
BEGIN:VEVENT
DTSTAMP:20060102T030405Z
DTSTART:20060102T030405Z
SUMMARY:hello
UID:CC0A494A-6E07-4827-8294-0752DD1ECFA4
END:VEVENT
END:VCALENDAR
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <t>A line containing just the value <tt>...</tt> stands for any other properties that might be present in a component but are irrelevant for this example.  This includes mandatory properties as described for implicit components.  The line <tt>...</tt> at the end of the example additionally stands for any END content lines to complete components that started with BEGIN content lines, and any of their missing mandatory properties. <xref target="example-notation-icalendar-dotdotdot"/> illustrates this as an alternative representation for the examples of <xref target="example-notation-icalendar-implicit-explicit"/>.</t>
          <figure anchor="example-notation-icalendar-dotdotdot">
            <name>Example for additional properties and component ENDs represented by <tt>...</tt>
            </name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VCALENDAR
BEGIN:VEVENT
SUMMARY:hello
...
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <t>A line starting with a single space represents the continuation of a folded content line (<xref target="RFC5545" section="3.1"/>).  <xref target="example-notation-icalendar-folded"/> illustrates this.</t>
          <figure anchor="example-notation-icalendar-folded">
            <name>Example for a folded content line</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
SUMMARY:he
 llo
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="notation-jscalendar">
          <name>JSCalendar Examples</name>
          <t>A JSCalendar example always represents a Group object, even if the example only depicts one of the Group entries or properties.</t>
          <t>JSCalendar objects are depicted either explicitly or implicitly. An explicit JSCalendar object starts and ends with braces.  An implicit JSCalendar object omits braces, it only consists of JSON name/value pairs, separated by comma.</t>
          <t>An implicit JSCalendar object is assumed to be of type Event, unless it contains the <tt>@type</tt> property with a different value.  It is assumed to contain all mandatory properties with some value; if they are not depicted, their actual value is irrelevant for the main point of the example.</t>
          <t><xref target="example-notation-jscalendar-implicit-explicit"/> illustrates this with multiple examples, all of which represent the same JSCalendar data.  The first example contains an implicit JSCalendar object of type Event.  The second example contains an implicit JSCalendar object with a <tt>@type</tt> property.  The third example contains an explicit Event object but the Group object containing it is omitted.  The fourth example contains the full Group object, nothing is omitted.</t>
          <figure anchor="example-notation-jscalendar-implicit-explicit">
            <name>Examples for implicit and explicit JSCalendar object notation</name>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"title": "hello"
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"@type": "Event",
"title": "hello"
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
{
  "@type": "Event",
  "title": "hello",
  "start": "2006-01-02T03:04:05",
  "timeZone": "Etc/UTC",
  "uid": "CC0A494A-6E07-4827-8294-0752DD1ECFA4",
  "updated": "2006-01-02T03:04:05Z"
}
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
{
  "@type": "Group",
  "entries": [
    {
      "@type": "Event",
      "title": "hello",
      "start": "2006-01-02T03:04:05",
      "timeZone": "Etc/UTC",
      "uid": "CC0A494A-6E07-4827-8294-0752DD1ECFA4",
      "updated": "2006-01-02T03:04:05Z"
    }
  ]
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <t>A property with name <tt>"..."</tt> and value <tt>""</tt> stands for additional properties that might be present in a JSCalendar object but are irrelevant for this example, including mandatory properties. The <tt>"..."</tt> property requires the <tt>"@type"</tt> property to be set. <xref target="example-notation-jscalendar-dotdotdot"/> illustrates this as an alternative representation for the examples of <xref target="example-notation-jscalendar-implicit-explicit"/>.</t>
          <figure anchor="example-notation-jscalendar-dotdotdot">
            <name>Example for additional properties represented by <tt>...</tt>
            </name>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
{
  "@type": "Event",
  "title": "hello",
  "...": ""
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section>
        <name>Lossy versus Lossless Conversion</name>
        <t>This document outlines how to convert iCalendar elements to JSCalendar elements, and the other way round. Many of these can be represented by standard elements in both formats, meaning that they are registered in the iCalendar and JSCalendar IANA registries and differ from the special-purpose elements introduced in <xref target="updates-icalendar"/> and <xref target="updates-jscalendar"/>. Still, a number of elements in either format have no standard counterpart in the other. When converting between between iCalendar and JSCalendar, implementations <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> choose to only convert elements that have standard element in the target format, or aim to preserve as many elements as possible.</t>
        <t>When to choose between lossy and lossless conversion is implementation-specific. For example:</t>
        <ul>
          <li>For lossy conversion, an implementation that internally stores calendar data in JSCalendar format might only want to convert to a subset of iCalendar elements for <xref target="RFC6047">iMIP scheduling</xref>. In this case, it might not make use any of the conversion-specific iCalendar properties introduced in <xref target="updates-icalendar"/>.</li>
          <li>For lossless conversion, an implementation that internally stores calendar data in iCalendar format might want to convert without loss to JSCalendar when updating calendar events with <xref target="jmap-calendars">JMAP</xref>. For that, it can use the conversion-specific properties defined in <xref target="updates-jscalendar"/>.</li>
        </ul>
        <t>All the examples in this document illustrate lossless conversion, if not explicitly stated otherwise in the example.</t>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section anchor="convert-icalendar-to-jscalendar">
      <name>Converting iCalendar to JSCalendar</name>
      <section anchor="ical-general">
        <name>General rules</name>
        <section anchor="ical-comp-vcalendar">
          <name>iCalendar Objects</name>
          <t><xref target="RFC5545" section="3.4"/> allows for an iCalendar stream to contain one or more iCalendar objects.  In contrast, this specification only defines conversion for streams consisting of a single iCalendar object. Converting streams of multiple iCalendar objects is implementation-specific.  All following sections of this document use the terms "iCalendar object" and "VCALENDAR component" interchangeably.</t>
          <t>The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.4" sectionFormat="parens">VCALENDAR component</xref> converts to a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="2.3" sectionFormat="parens">Group object</xref>.  Its properties convert as follows:</t>
          <table anchor="ical-comp-vcalendar-props">
            <name>Properties of the VCALENDAR component</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Name</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>Group property</th>
                <th>See</th>
                <th>Note</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>ATTACH</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>links</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-attach"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>CATEGORIES</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>keywords</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-categories"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>COLOR</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.9" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>color</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-color"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>CONCEPT</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9253" section="8.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>categories</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-concept"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>CREATED</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.7.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>created</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-created"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DESCRIPTION</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>description</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-description"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>IMAGE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.10" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>links</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-image"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>LAST-MODIFIED</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.7.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>updated</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-last-modified"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>LINK</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9253" section="8.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>links</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-link"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>METHOD</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.7.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>entries/*/method</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-method"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>NAME</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>title</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-name"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>PRODID</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.7.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>prodId, entries/*/prodId</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-prodid"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>SOURCE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.8" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>source</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-source"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>UID</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.7" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>uid</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-uid"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>Its components convert as follows:</t>
          <table anchor="ical-comp-vcalendar-comps">
            <name>Components of the VCALENDAR component</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Name</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>Group property</th>
                <th>See</th>
                <th>Note</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>VEVENT</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.6.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>entries</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-comp-vevent"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>VTODO</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.6.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>entries</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-comp-vtodo"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>Other properties or components <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> be converted to the <xref target="jscal-prop-icalcomponent">"iCalComponent" property</xref> of the Group object.</t>
          <t>The order of elements in the "entries" property is implementation-specific, e.g. entries need not be in the same order as their source components in the iCalendar object.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the VCALENDAR component:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-comp-vcalendar">
            <name>Converting the VCALENDAR component</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VCALENDAR
UID:41aa02b6-42d0-4f45-8cb4-8b5075be2e14
BEGIN:VEVENT
...
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
{
  "@type": "Group",
  "entries": [
    {
      "...": "",
      "@type": "Event"
    }
  ],
  "uid": "41aa02b6-42d0-4f45-8cb4-8b5075be2e14",
  "...": "",
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-recurring-components">
          <name>Recurring Components</name>
          <t>Components in an iCalendar object generally convert to distinct JSCalendar objects. For example, two VEVENT components with different UID property values in the same iCalendar object convert to two separate Event objects in the Group object's entries. As an exception to this rule, this does not apply to recurrence overrides, defined as follows.</t>
          <t>A VEVENT (or VTODO) component is a recurrence override if it has the RECURRENCE-ID property set, and the iCalendar object contains a VEVENT (or VTODO) component that does not have the RECURRENCE-ID but the RRULE property set, and the UID property values of the two components are equal. The component without the RECURRENCE-ID property is in that case referred to as the "main component".</t>
          <t>The main component converts to an entry in the Group object's entries property.</t>
          <t>The recurrence override converts to the "recurrenceOverrides" property of the converted main component. Its RECURRENCE-ID property value converts to the key in the "recurrenceOverrides" property. The value of the "recurrenceOverrides" property at that key is a PatchObject that transform the converted main component into the converted recurrence override. The recurrenceId and recurrenceIdTimeZone properties <bcp14>MUST NOT</bcp14> be set in the PatchObject.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert a main component and its recurrence override:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-comp-vevent-recurrence-overrides">
            <name>Converting VEVENT recurrence overrides</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VCALENDAR
BEGIN:VEVENT
UID:F4257E1D-5461-4EF6-840F-9DFC653EB559
RRULE:FREQ=DAILY
DTSTART;TZID=Europe/Berlin:20240101T140000
...
END:VEVENT
BEGIN:VEVENT
UID:F4257E1D-5461-4EF6-840F-9DFC653EB559
RECURRENCE-ID;TZID=Europe/Berlin:20240202T140000
DTSTART;TZID=Europe/Berlin:20240202T160000
...
END:VEVENT
END:VCALENDAR
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
{
  "@type": "Group",
  "entries": [
    {
      "...": "",
      "@type": "Event",
      "recurrenceOverrides": {
        "2024-02-02T14:00:00": {
          "start": "2024-02-02T16:00:00"
        }
      },
      "recurrenceRule": {
        "@type": "RecurrenceRule",
        "frequency": "daily"
      },
      "start": "2024-01-01T14:00:00",
      "timeZone": "Europe/Berlin",
      "uid": "F4257E1D-5461-4EF6-840F-9DFC653EB559"
    }
  ],
  "...": ""
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <t>A VEVENT (or VTODO) component is a stand-alone recurrence instance if it has the RECURRENCE-ID property set and the iCalendar object does not contain its related main component. Each stand-alone recurrence instance converts to a distinct Event (or Task) object in the Group object's entries property.  The recurrenceId property <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be set, the "recurrenceIdTimeZone" property <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be set if not "null".</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert stand-alone recurrence instances:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-comp-vevent-recurrence-instances">
            <name>Converting VEVENT recurrence instances</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VCALENDAR
BEGIN:VEVENT
UID:F4257E1D-5461-4EF6-840F-9DFC653EB559
RECURRENCE-ID;TZID=Europe/Berlin:20240202T140000
DTSTART;TZID=Europe/Berlin:20240202T160000
...
END:VEVENT
BEGIN:VEVENT
UID:F4257E1D-5461-4EF6-840F-9DFC653EB559
RECURRENCE-ID;TZID=Europe/Berlin:20240103T140000
DTSTART;TZID=Europe/Berlin:20240103T170000
...
END:VEVENT
END:VCALENDAR
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
{
  "@type": "Group",
  "entries": [
    {
      "...": "",
      "@type": "Event",
      "recurrenceId": "2024-02-02T14:00:00",
      "recurrenceIdTimeZone": "Europe/Berlin",
      "start": "2024-02-02T16:00:00",
      "timeZone": "Europe/Berlin",
      "uid": "F4257E1D-5461-4EF6-840F-9DFC653EB559"
    },
    {
      "...": "",
      "@type": "Event",
      "recurrenceId": "2024-01-03T14:00:00",
      "recurrenceIdTimeZone": "Europe/Berlin",
      "start": "2024-01-03T17:00:00",
      "timeZone": "Europe/Berlin",
      "uid": "F4257E1D-5461-4EF6-840F-9DFC653EB559"
    }
  ],
  "...": ""
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="generating-jscalendar-ids">
          <name>JSCalendar Ids</name>
          <t>JSCalendar generally uses JSON objects to represent a collection of same-typed values. The keys are of type <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="1.4.1" sectionFormat="parens">Id</xref>, the values are JSCalendar object types.  If an iCalendar element converts to a value in such a collection, then an implementation needs to choose an identifier as key.</t>
          <t>This document defines the new <xref target="ical-param-jsid">JSID</xref> parameter and <xref target="ical-prop-jsid">JSID property</xref>, which allow to set a JSCalendar Id value when converting from JSCalendar to iCalendar.  If they are set on a property or the component, then its value <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be used as key when converting that element from iCalendar to JSCalendar.  If no such parameter or property is set, then an implementation is free to choose any identifier, as long the following requirements are met:</t>
          <ul>
            <li>The identifier <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be a valid Id value.</li>
            <li>The identifiers for the exact same iCalendar element <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> stay the same, irrespective of the order in which components, properties and parameters are processed.</li>
          </ul>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-timezone-identifiers">
          <name>Timezone identifiers</name>
          <t>Converting temporal properties such as DTSTART, DTEND, and RECURRENCE-ID requires to not only determine the date and time of the property value, but also the timezone it references.</t>
          <t>If the property value type is <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.3.4" sectionFormat="parens">DATE</xref> or  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.3.5" sectionFormat="parens">DATE-TIME in FORM #1: DATE WITH LOCAL TIME</xref> then the timezone identifier is the JSON null value in JSCalendar.</t>
          <t>If the property value type is <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.3.5" sectionFormat="parens">DATE-TIME in FORM #2: DATE WITH UTC TIME</xref> then the timezone identifier is the string "Etc/UTC" in JSCalendar.</t>
          <t>If the property value type is <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.3.5" sectionFormat="parens">DATE-TIME in FORM #3: DATE WITH LOCAL TIME AND TIME ZONE REFERENCE</xref> then the timezone identifier is determined by the TZID parameter value:</t>
          <t>If the TZID parameter value is equal to a name in the <xref target="TZDB">IANA Time Zone Database</xref> then the timezone identifier is that verbatim name. Otherwise, how to convert the TZID parameter value is implementation-specific: software libraries such as the <eref target="https://icu.unicode.org/">International Components for Unicode</eref> support converting Microsoft time zone names to IANA time zone identifiers. Alternatively, finding an IANA time zone for which the time zone offset changes match those of the custom time zone over the span of the event or task is typically possible.</t>
        </section>
        <section anchor="convert-date-and-date-time">
          <name>DATE and DATE-TIME</name>
          <t>iCalendar provides the DATE and DATE-TIME value types to distinguish date-only from date-time values. JSCalendar only supports date-time values.  A property value of type DATE-TIME converts to either a LocalDateTime or UTCDateTime, depending on the JSCalendar property definition. A DATE value type converts to a LocalDateTime with zero time.</t>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section anchor="ical-components">
        <name>Components</name>
        <section anchor="ical-comp-participant">
          <name>PARTICIPANT</name>
          <t>The <xref target="RFC9073" section="7.1" sectionFormat="parens">PARTICIPANT component</xref> converts to a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="parens">Participant object</xref>.  Its properties convert as follows:</t>
          <table anchor="ical-comp-participant-props">
            <name>Properties of the PARTICIPANT component</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Name</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>Participant property</th>
                <th>See</th>
                <th>Note</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>ATTACH</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>links</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-attach"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>CALENDAR-ADDRESS</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9073" section="6.4" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>calendarAddress</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-calendar-address"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DESCRIPTION</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>description</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-description"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DTSTAMP</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.7.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>updated</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-dtstamp"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>GEO</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>locations</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-geo"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>LINK</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9253" section="8.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>links</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-link"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>STYLED-DESCRIPTION</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9073" section="6.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>description</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-styled-description"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>SUMMARY</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.12" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>name</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-summary"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>Other properties or components <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> be converted to the <xref target="jscal-prop-icalcomponent">"iCalComponent" property</xref> of the Participant object. This includes mandatory properties such as <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.7" sectionFormat="parens">UID</xref>.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the PARTICIPANT component:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-comp-participant">
            <name>Converting the PARTICIPANT component</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
BEGIN:PARTICIPANT
UID:47AD2E1C-49D4-45DF-BD83-8398ACC7D8E2
DESCRIPTION:A participant
END:PARTICIPANT
...
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
{
  "...": "",
  "@type": "Event",
  "participants": {
    "p32": {
      "@type": "Participant",
      "description": "A participant",
      "iCalComponent": {
        "@type": "ICalComponent",
        "name": "participant",
        "properties": [
          [
            "uid",
            {},
            "text",
            "47AD2E1C-49D4-45DF-BD83-8398ACC7D8E2"
          ]
        ]
      }
    }
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-comp-valarm">
          <name>VALARM</name>
          <t>The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.6.6" sectionFormat="parens">VALARM component</xref> converts to an <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.5.2" sectionFormat="parens">Alert object</xref>.  Its properties convert as follows:</t>
          <table anchor="ical-comp-valarm-props">
            <name>Properties of the VALARM component</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Name</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>Alert property</th>
                <th>See</th>
                <th>Note</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>ACKNOWLEDGED</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9074" section="6.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>acknowledged</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-acknowledged"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>ACTION</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.6.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>action</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-action"/>
                </td>
                <td>Only if ACTION is EMAIL or DISPLAY.</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>RELATED-TO</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>relatedTo</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-related-to"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>TRIGGER</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.6.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>trigger</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-trigger"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>Other properties or components <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> be converted to the <xref target="jscal-prop-icalcomponent">"iCalComponent" property</xref> of the Alert object. This includes mandatory properties such as <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.1" sectionFormat="parens">ATTENDEE</xref>, <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.5" sectionFormat="parens">DESCRIPTION</xref>, or <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.12" sectionFormat="parens">SUMMARY</xref>.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the VALARM component:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-comp-valarm">
            <name>Converting the VALARM component</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
BEGIN:VALARM
TRIGGER:-PT30M
ACTION:DISPLAY
DESCRIPTION:Breakfast meeting
END:VALARM
...
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
{
  "...": "",
  "@type": "Event",
  "alerts": {
    "a8": {
      "@type": "Alert",
      "iCalComponent": {
        "@type": "ICalComponent",
        "name": "valarm",
        "properties": [
          [
            "description",
            {},
            "text",
            "Breakfast meeting"
          ]
        ]
      },
      "trigger": {
        "@type": "OffsetTrigger",
        "offset": "-PT30M"
      },
      "action": "display"
    }
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-comp-vconference">
          <name>VCONFERENCE</name>
          <t>The <xref target="icaljscalexts" section="6.1" sectionFormat="parens">VCONFERENCE component</xref> converts to a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.7" sectionFormat="parens">VirtualLocation object</xref>.  It <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> convert to the same VirtualLocation to which its related <xref target="ical-prop-conference">CONFERENCE property</xref> converts. Its properties convert as follows:</t>
          <table anchor="ical-comp-vconference-props">
            <name>Properties of the VCONFERENCE component</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Name</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>Location property</th>
                <th>See</th>
                <th>Note</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>DESCRIPTION</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>description</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-description"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>STYLED-DESCRIPTION</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9073" section="6.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>description</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-styled-description"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>Other properties or components <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> be converted to the <xref target="jscal-prop-icalcomponent">"iCalComponent" property</xref> of the VirtualLocation object.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the VCONFERENCE component:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-comp-vconference">
            <name>Converting the VCONFERENCE component</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VCONFERENCE
URI;VALUE=URI:https://chat.example.com/x?id=123456
STYLED-DESCRIPTION;VALUE=TEXT;FMTTYPE=text/html:<body>Click <a
 href="https://chat.example.com/client">here</a> to download t
 he client..</body>
...
END:VCONFERENCE
CONFERENCE;VALUE=URI;FEATURE=AUDIO,VIDEO;
 LABEL=Team meeting:https://chat.example.com/x?id=123456
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"virtualLocations": {
  "1": {
    "@type": "VirtualLocation",
    "name": "Team meeting",
    "description": "<body>Click <a href="https://chat.example.com/client">here</a> to download the client...</body>",
    "descriptionContentType": "text/html",
    "uri": "https://chat.example.com/x?id=123456",
    "features": {
      "audio": true,
      "video": true
    }
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-comp-vevent">
          <name>VEVENT</name>
          <t>The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.6.1" sectionFormat="parens">VEVENT component</xref> converts to a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="2.1" sectionFormat="parens">Event object</xref>.  Its properties convert as follows:</t>
          <table anchor="ical-comp-vevent-props">
            <name>Properties of the VEVENT component</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Name</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>Event property</th>
                <th>See</th>
                <th>Note</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>ATTACH</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>links</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-attach"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>ATTENDEE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>participants</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-attendee"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>CATEGORIES</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>keywords</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-categories"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>CLASS</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>privacy</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-class"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>COLOR</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.9" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>color</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-color"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>CONCEPT</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9253" section="8.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>categories</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-concept"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>CONFERENCE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.11" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>virtualLocations</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-conference"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>CREATED</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.7.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>created</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-created"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DESCRIPTION</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>description</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-description"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DTEND</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.2.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>duration, endTimeZone</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-dtend"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DTSTAMP</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.7.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>updated</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-dtstamp"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DTSTART</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.2.4" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>start</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-dtstart"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DURATION</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.2.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>duration</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-duration"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>EXDATE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.5.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>recurrenceOverrides</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-exdate"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>GEO</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>locations</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-geo"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>IMAGE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.10" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>links</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-image"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>LAST-MODIFIED</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.7.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>updated</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-last-modified"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>LINK</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9253" section="8.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>links</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-link"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>LOCATION</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.7" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>locations</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-location"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>ORGANIZER</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>organizerCalendarAddress</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-organizer"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>PRIORITY</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.9" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>priority</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-priority"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>RDATE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.5.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>recurrenceOverrides</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-rdate"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>RECURRENCE-ID</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.4" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>recurrenceId</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-recurrence-id"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>RELATED-TO</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>relatedTo</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-related-to"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>RRULE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.5.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>recurrenceRule</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-rrule"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>SEQUENCE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.7.4" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>sequence</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-sequence"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>STATUS</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.11" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>status</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-status"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>STYLED-DESCRIPTION</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9073" section="6.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>description</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-styled-description"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>SUMMARY</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.12" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>title</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-summary"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>TRANSP</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.2.7" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>freeBusyStatus</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-transp"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>UID</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.7" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>uid</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-uid"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>Its components convert as follows:</t>
          <table anchor="ical-comp-vevent-comps">
            <name>Components of the  VEVENT component</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Name</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>Event property</th>
                <th>See</th>
                <th>Note</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>VALARM</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.6.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>alerts</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-comp-valarm"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>Other properties or components <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> be converted to the <xref target="jscal-prop-icalcomponent">"iCalComponent" property</xref> of the Event object.</t>
          <t>VEVENT components with different UID property values in the same iCalendar object convert to different entries in the Group.  They sort in the same order as in the VCALENDAR component.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the VEVENT component:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-comp-vevent">
            <name>Converting the VEVENT component</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VCALENDAR
BEGIN:VEVENT
UID:DE935D01-3DF7-4201-B61A-D77D05C8B21A
DTSTART:20060102T030405Z
...
END:VEVENT
BEGIN:VEVENT
UID:60BE3D6E-6383-473A-BCF1-3C43EA1FA571
...
END:VEVENT
END:VCALENDAR
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
{
  "...": "",
  "@type": "Group",
  "entries": [
    {
      "@type": "Event",
      "start": "2006-01-02T03:04:05",
      "timeZone": "Etc/UTC",
      "uid": "DE935D01-3DF7-4201-B61A-D77D05C8B21A",
      "...": ""
    },
    {
      "@type": "Event",
      "uid": "60BE3D6E-6383-473A-BCF1-3C43EA1FA571",
      "...": ""
    }
  ]
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-comp-vlocation">
          <name>VLOCATION</name>
          <t>The <xref target="RFC9073" section="7.2" sectionFormat="parens">VLOCATION component</xref> converts to a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="parens">Location object</xref>.  Its properties convert as follows:</t>
          <table anchor="ical-comp-vlocation-props">
            <name>Properties of the VLOCATION component</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Name</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>Location property</th>
                <th>See</th>
                <th>Note</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>ATTACH</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>links</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-attach"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>COORDINATES</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="icaljscalexts" section="4.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>coordinates</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-coordinates"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DESCRIPTION</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>description</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-description"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>GEO</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>coordinates</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-geo"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>IMAGE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.10" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>links</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-image"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>LINK</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9253" section="8.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>links</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-link"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>LOCATION-TYPE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9073" section="6.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>locationTypes</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-location-type"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>NAME</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>name</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-name"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>STYLED-DESCRIPTION</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9073" section="6.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>description</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-styled-description"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>Other properties or components <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> be converted to the <xref target="jscal-prop-icalcomponent">"iCalComponent" property</xref> of the Location object. This includes mandatory properties such as <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.7" sectionFormat="parens">UID</xref>.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the VLOCATION component:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-comp-vlocation">
            <name>Converting the VLOCATION component</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VLOCATION
UID:4954DC22-5BD6-4E98-844D-0302982F54AC
NAME:The venue
STRUCTURED-DATA;VALUE=URI:
 http://dir.example.com/venues/big-hall.vcf
END:VLOCATION
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"locations": {
  "e4": {
    "@type": "Location",
    "name": "The venue",
    "iCalComponent": {
      "@type": "ICalComponent",
      "name": "vlocation",
      "properties": [
        [
          "structured-data",
          {},
          "uri",
          "http://dir.example.com/venues/big-hall.vcf"
        ],
        [
          "uid",
          {},
          "text",
          "4954DC22-5BD6-4E98-844D-0302982F54AC"
        ]
      ]
    }
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-comp-vtodo">
          <name>VTODO</name>
          <t>The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.6.2" sectionFormat="parens">VTODO component</xref> converts to a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="2.2" sectionFormat="parens">Task object</xref>.  Its properties convert as follows:</t>
          <table anchor="ical-comp-vtodo-props">
            <name>Properties of the VTODO component</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Name</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>Task property</th>
                <th>See</th>
                <th>Note</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>ATTACH</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>links</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-attach"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>ATTENDEE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>participants</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-attendee"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>CATEGORIES</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>keywords</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-categories"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>CLASS</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>privacy</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-class"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>COLOR</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.9" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>color</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-color"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>CONCEPT</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9253" section="8.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>categories</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-concept"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>CONFERENCE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.11" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>virtualLocations</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-conference"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>CREATED</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.7.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>created</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-created"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DESCRIPTION</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>description</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-description"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DTSTAMP</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.7.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>updated</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-dtstamp"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DTSTART</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.2.4" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>start</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-dtstart"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DUE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.2.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>due</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-due"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DURATION</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.2.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>duration</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-duration"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>ESTIMATED-DURATION</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-tasks" section="12.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>estimatedDuration</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-estimated-duration"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>EXDATE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.5.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>recurrenceOverrides</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-exdate"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>GEO</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>locations</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-geo"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>IMAGE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.10" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>links</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-image"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>LAST-MODIFIED</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.7.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>updated</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-last-modified"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>LINK</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9253" section="8.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>links</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-link"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>LOCATION</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.7" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>locations</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-location"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>ORGANIZER</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>organizerCalendarAddress</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-organizer"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>PERCENT-COMPLETE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.8" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>percentComplete</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-percent-complete"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>PRIORITY</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.9" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>priority</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-priority"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>RDATE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.5.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>recurrenceOverrides</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-rdate"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>RECURRENCE-ID</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.4" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>recurrenceId</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-recurrence-id"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>RELATED-TO</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>relatedTo</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-related-to"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>RRULE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.5.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>recurrenceRule</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-rrule"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>SEQUENCE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.7.4" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>sequence</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-sequence"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>STYLED-DESCRIPTION</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9073" section="6.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>description</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-styled-description"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>SUMMARY</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.12" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>title</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-summary"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>TRANSP</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.2.7" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>freeBusyStatus</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-transp"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>UID</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.7" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>uid</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-uid"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>Its components convert as follows:</t>
          <table anchor="ical-comp-vtodo-comps">
            <name>Components of the  VTODO component</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Name</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>Task property</th>
                <th>See</th>
                <th>Note</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>VALARM</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.6.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>alerts</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-comp-valarm"/>
                </td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>Other properties or components <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> be converted to the <xref target="jscal-prop-icalcomponent">"iCalComponent" property</xref> of the Task object.</t>
          <t>VTODO components with different UID property values in the same iCalendar object convert to different entries in the Group.  They sort in the same order as in the VCALENDAR component.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the VTODO component:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-comp-vtodo">
            <name>Converting the VTODO component</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VCALENDAR
BEGIN:VTODO
UID:83C80482-806D-41C4-8029-E438F793005D
DUE:20060102T030405Z
...
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
{
  "...": "",
  "@type": "Group",
  "entries": [
    {
      "...": "",
      "@type": "Task",
      "due": "2006-01-02T03:04:05",
      "timeZone": "Etc/UTC",
      "uid": "83C80482-806D-41C4-8029-E438F793005D"
    }
  ]
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section anchor="ical-properties">
        <name>Properties</name>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-acknowledged">
          <name>ACKNOWLEDGED</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC9074" section="6.1" sectionFormat="parens">ACKNOWLEDGED property</xref> in a VALARM component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.5.2" sectionFormat="parens">"acknowledged" property</xref> of the Alert object.
          </t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the ACKNOWLEDGED property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-acknowledged">
            <name>Converting the ACKNOWLEDGED property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
BEGIN:VALARM
ACKNOWLEDGED:20241002T114703Z
...
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"alerts": {
  "a": {
    "@type": "Alert",
    "acknowledged": "2024-10-02T11:47:03Z",
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-action">
          <name>ACTION</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.6.1" sectionFormat="parens">ACTION property</xref> in a VALARM component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.5.2" sectionFormat="parens">"action" property</xref> of the Alert object.
          </t>
          <t>Its values convert as follows:</t>
          <table anchor="ical-prop-action-values">
            <name>Values of the ACTION property</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>iCalendar value</th>
                <th>JSCalendar value</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>DISPLAY</td>
                <td>display</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>EMAIL</td>
                <td>email</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>An ACTION property with value AUDIO or any other not listed in <xref target="ical-prop-action-values"/> does not convert to the "action" property. Instead, the property converts to the <xref target="jscal-prop-icalcomponent">iCalComponent/properties property</xref> of the Alert.</t>
          <t>The following examples illustrate how to convert the ACTION property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-action-display">
            <name>Converting the ACTION property for value DISPLAY</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
BEGIN:VALARM
ACTION:DISPLAY
...
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"alerts": {
  "a": {
    "@type": "Alert",
    "action": "display",
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-action-audio">
            <name>Converting the ACTION property for value AUDIO</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
BEGIN:VALARM
ACTION:AUDIO
...
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"alerts": {
  "a": {
    "@type": "Alert",
    "iCalComponent": {
      "@type": "ICalComponent",
      "name": "valarm",
      "properties": [
        [
          "action",
          {},
          "text",
          "AUDIO"
        ]
      ]
    },
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-attach">
          <name>ATTACH</name>
          <t>
              The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.1" sectionFormat="parens">ATTACH property</xref> in a VEVENT, VTODO, PARTICIPANT, VLOCATION, or VCALENDAR component converts to a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="1.4.11" sectionFormat="parens">Link object</xref>.  The converted object is set in the "links" property of the Event, Task, Participant, Location, or Group object.
          </t>
          <t>The property value converts to the "href" property of the Link object. A value of type URI converts as-is. A value of type BINARY converts to a URI in the "data" URL scheme (<xref target="RFC2397"/>. If the FMTTYPE parameter is set on the ATTACH property, then the parameter value <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be set in the "mediatype" part of the data URL.</t>
          <t>The ATTACH property parameters convert as follows:</t>
          <table>
            <name>Parameters of the ATTACH property</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Name</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>Link Property</th>
                <th>Note</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>FMTTYPE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.8" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>contentType</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>LABEL</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="6.4" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>title</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>LINKREL</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9253" section="6.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>rel</td>
                <td>See remarks below</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>SIZE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC8607" section="4.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>size</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>Remarks:</t>
          <ul>
            <li>The LINKREL parameter value is defined to be either an URI or an <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.1" sectionFormat="parens">"iana-token"</xref>. Only parameter values of form "iana-token" convert to the "rel" property of the Link object. The values convert to lowercase.</li>
          </ul>
          <t>The following examples illustrate how to convert the ATTACH property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-attach-uri">
            <name>Converting the ATTACH property with URI value</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
ATTACH:https://example.com/foo.pdf
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"links": {
  "a": {
    "@type": "Link",
    "href": "https://example.com/foo.pdf"
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-attach-binary">
            <name>Converting the ATTACH property with BINARY value</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
ATTACH;ENCODING=BASE64;VALUE=BINARY;FMTTYPE=image/png:iVBORw
 0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAEAAAABAQAAAAA3bvkkAAAAAmJLR0QAAd2KE6QAA
 AAKSURBVAjXY2gAAACCAIHdQ2r0AAAAAElFTkSuQmCC
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"links": {
  "a": {
    "@type": "Link",
    "href": "data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAEAAAABAQAAAAA3bvkkAAAAAmJLR0QAAd2KE6QAAAAKSURBVAjXY2gAAACCAIHdQ2r0AAAAAElFTkSuQmCC",
    "contentType": "image/png",
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-attendee">
          <name>ATTENDEE</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.1" sectionFormat="parens">ATTENDEE property</xref> in a VEVENT or VTODO component converts to a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="parens">Participant object</xref>.  The converted object is set in the "participants" property of the Event or Task object. The property value converts to the calendarAddress property of the Participant object.</t>
          <t>An ATTENDEE property and a PARTICIPANT component in the same iCalendar component convert to the same Participant object, if their converted calendarAddress property values are equal. How to deal with conflicting values is implementation-specific.</t>
          <t>The ATTENDEE property parameters convert as follows:</t>
          <table>
            <name>Parameters of the ATTENDEE property</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Name</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>Participant Property</th>
                <th>Note</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>CN</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>name</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>CUTYPE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>kind</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DELEGATED-FROM</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.4" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>delegatedFrom</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DELEGATED-TO</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>delegatedTo</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>EMAIL</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="6.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>email</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>MEMBER</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.11" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>memberOf</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>PARTSTAT</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.12" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>participationStatus</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>ROLE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.16" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>roles</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>RSVP</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.17" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>expectReply</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>SENT-BY</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.18" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>sentBy</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>If no ROLE parameter is set, then the "attendee" role in the "roles" property <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be set.</t>
          <t>The PARTSTAT of an ATTENDEE property in a VTODO component converts not only to the "participationStatus" property of the Participant object, but also to its progress property if the PARTSTAT parameter value is specific for VTODO components:</t>
          <table anchor="ical-prop-attendee-param-partstat">
            <name>Converting the PARTSTAT parameter in a VTODO component to Participant properties</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>PARTSTAT</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>participationStatus</th>
                <th>progress</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>NEEDS-ACTION</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.12" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>needs-action</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>ACCEPTED</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.12" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>accepted</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DECLINED</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.12" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>declined</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>TENTATIVE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.12" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>tentative</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DELEGATED</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.12" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>delegated</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>COMPLETED</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.12" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>accepted</td>
                <td>completed</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>IN-PROCESS</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.12" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>accepted</td>
                <td>in-process</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>FAILED</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="ical-tasks" section="11.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>accepted</td>
                <td>failed</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>The following examples illustrate how to convert the ATTENDEE property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-attendee">
            <name>Converting the ATTENDEE property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
ATTENDEE;RSVP=TRUE;PARTSTAT=TENTATIVE;CN=Henry Cabot:mailto:hcabot@example.com
ORGANIZER:mailto:organizer@example.com
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"participants": {
  "p3": {
    "@type": "Participant",
    "calendarAddress": "mailto:hcabot@example.com",
    "name": "Henry Cabot",
    "participationStatus": "tentative",
    "roles": {
      "attendee": true
    },
    "expectReply": true
  },
  "o4": {
    "@type": "Participant",
    "calendarAddress": "mailto:organizer@example.com",
    "roles": {
      "owner": true
    }
  }
},
"organizerCalendarAddress": "mailto:organizer@example.com"
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-attendee-participant">
            <name>Converting the ATTENDEE property and PARTICIPANT component</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:PARTICIPANT
CALENDAR-ADDRESS:mailto:foo@example.com
DESCRIPTION:some description
...
END:PARTICIPANT
ATTENDEE;RSVP=TRUE;PARTSTAT=TENTATIVE:mailto:foo@example.com
ORGANIZER:mailto:organizer@example.com
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"participants": {
  "23": {
    "@type": "Participant",
    "calendarAddress": "mailto:foo@example.com",
    "participationStatus": "tentative",
    "expectReply": true,
    "description": "some description",
    "...": ""
  },
  "o4": {
    "@type": "Participant",
    "calendarAddress": "mailto:organizer@example.com",
    "...": ""
  }
},
"organizerCalendarAddress": "mailto:organizer@example.com"
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-attendee-vtodo-partstat">
            <name>Converting the ATTENDEE property with a VTODO-specific participation status</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VTODO
ATTENDEE;RSVP=TRUE;PARTSTAT=COMPLETED:mailto:foo@example.com
ORGANIZER:mailto:organizer@example.com
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"@type": "Task",
"participants": {
  "1": {
    "@type": "Participant",
    "calendarAddress": "mailto:foo@example.com",
    "participationStatus": "accepted",
    "progress": "completed",
    "expectReply": true,
    "...": ""
  },
  "o": {
    "@type": "Participant",
    "calendarAddress": "mailto:organizer@example.com",
    "...": ""
  }
},
"organizerCalendarAddress": "mailto:organizer@example.com"
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-calendar-address">
          <name>CALENDAR-ADDRESS</name>
          <t>
              The <xref target="RFC9073" section="6.4" sectionFormat="parens">CALENDAR-ADDRESS property</xref> in a PARTICIPANT component converts to the <xref target="jmap-calendars" section="5.1.1" sectionFormat="parens">"calendarAddress" property</xref> of the Participant object.
          </t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the CALENDAR-ADDRESS property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-calendar-address">
            <name>Converting the CALENDAR-ADDRESS property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:PARTICIPANT
CALENDAR-ADDRESS:mailto:foo@example.com
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"participants": {
  "a2": {
    "@type": "Participant",
    "calendarAddress": "mailto:foo@example.com",
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-categories">
          <name>CATEGORIES</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.2" sectionFormat="parens">CATEGORIES property</xref> in a VEVENT, VTODO, or VCALENDAR component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.9" sectionFormat="parens">"keywords" property</xref> of the Event, Task, or Group object.
          </t>
          <t>The list of category values converts to a set of keywords. The values convert case-sensitively. All CATEGORIES properties in the same iCalendar component convert to the "keywords" property in the JSCalendar object.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the CATEGORIES property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-categories">
            <name>Converting the CATEGORIES property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
CATEGORIES:APPOINTMENT,EDUCATION
CATEGORIES:meeting
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"keywords": {
  "APPOINTMENT": true,
  "EDUCATION": true,
  "meeting": true
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-class">
          <name>CLASS</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.3" sectionFormat="parens">CLASS property</xref> in a VEVENT or VTODO component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.3" sectionFormat="parens">"privacy" property</xref> of the Event or Task object.
          </t>
          <t>Its values convert as follows:</t>
          <table anchor="ical-prop-class-values">
            <name>Values of the CLASS property</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>iCalendar value</th>
                <th>JSCalendar value</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>PUBLIC</td>
                <td>public</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>PRIVATE</td>
                <td>private</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>CONFIDENTIAL</td>
                <td>secret</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>Any other value does not convert to the "class" property. Instead, the property converts to the <xref target="jscal-prop-icalcomponent">iCalComponent/properties property</xref> of the JSCalendar object.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the CLASS property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-class">
            <name>Converting the CLASS property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
CLASS:PRIVATE
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"privacy": "private"
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-color">
          <name>COLOR</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.9" sectionFormat="parens">COLOR property</xref> in a VEVENT, VTODO, or VCALENDAR component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.11" sectionFormat="parens">"color" property</xref> of the Event, Task, or Group object.
          </t>
          <t>Its value converts verbatim.</t>
          <t>The following examples illustrate how to convert the COLOR property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-color-name">
            <name>Converting the COLOR property with color name</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
COLOR:maroon
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"color": "maroon"
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-color-numeric">
            <name>Converting the COLOR property with numeric value</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
COLOR:#ffa07a
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"color": "#ffa07a"
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-concept">
          <name>CONCEPT</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC9253" section="8.1" sectionFormat="parens">CONCEPT property</xref> in a VEVENT, VTODO, or VCALENDAR component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.10" sectionFormat="parens">"categories" property</xref> of the Event, Task, or Group object.
          </t>
          <t>The list of URI values converts to a set of URIs. Multiple occurrences of the CONCEPT property in the same iCalendar component convert to the same categories property in the JSCalendar object.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the CONCEPT property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-concept">
            <name>Converting the CONCEPT property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
CONCEPT:https://example.com/event-types/arts/music
CONCEPT:https://example.com/event-types/arts/literature
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"categories": {
  "https://example.com/event-types/arts/music": true,
  "https://example.com/event-types/arts/literature": true
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-conference">
          <name>CONFERENCE</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.11" sectionFormat="parens">CONFERENCE property</xref> in a VEVENT or VTODO component converts to a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.6" sectionFormat="parens">VirtualLocation object</xref>.  The converted object is set in the "virtualLocations" property of the Event or Task object. The property value converts to the "uri" property of the VirtualLocation object.</t>
          <t>The CONFERENCE property and a VCONFERENCE component convert to the same VirtualLocation, if the CONFERENCE property value matches the URI property value of the VCONFERENCE component. Also see <xref target="ical-comp-vconference"/>.</t>
          <t>Its parameters convert as follows:</t>
          <table>
            <name>Parameters of the CONFERENCE property</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Name</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>Property</th>
                <th>Note</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>FEATURE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="6.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>features</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>LABEL</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="6.4" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>name</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the CONFERENCE property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-conference">
            <name>Converting the CONFERENCE property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
CONFERENCE;VALUE=URI;FEATURE=AUDIO,VIDEO;
 LABEL="Web video chat, access code=76543"
 :https://chat.example.com/audio?id=123456
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"virtualLocations": {
  "b2": {
    "@type": "VirtualLocation",
    "name": "Web video chat, access code=76543",
    "uri": "https://chat.example.com/audio?id=123456",
    "features": {
      "audio": true,
      "video": true
    }
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-coordinates">
          <name>COORDINATES</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="icaljscalexts" section="4.1" sectionFormat="parens">COORDINATES property</xref> in a VLOCATION component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="parens">"coordinates" property</xref> of the Location object.</t>
         <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the COORDINATES property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-coordinates">
            <name>Converting the COORDINATES property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
GEO;DERIVED=TRUE:48.198634;16.371648
BEGIN:VLOCATION
COORDINATES;VALUE=URI:geo:48.198634,16.371648;crs=wgs84;u=40
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"locations": {
  "1": {
    "@type": "Location",
    "coordinates": "geo:48.198634,16.371648;crs=wgs84;u=40",
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-created">
          <name>CREATED</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.7.1" sectionFormat="parens">CREATED property</xref> in a VEVENT, VTODO, or VCALENDAR component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.5" sectionFormat="parens">"created" property</xref> of the Event, Task, or Group object.
          </t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the CREATED property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-created">
            <name>Converting the CREATED property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
CREATED:20240329T133000Z
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"created": "2024-03-29T13:30:00Z"
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-description">
          <name>DESCRIPTION</name>
          <t>The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.5" sectionFormat="parens">DESCRIPTION property</xref> in a VEVENT, VTODO, VCALENDAR, VLOCATION, or PARTICIPANT component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.2" sectionFormat="parens">"description" property</xref> of the Event, Task, Group, Location, Link, or Participant object, unless its DERIVED parameter value is TRUE.</t>
          <t>If the DERIVED parameter value is TRUE, then the property does not convert to the "description" property. Instead, a non-derived STYLED-DESCRIPTION property is expected to contain the description. Implementations MAY preserve the property in the <xref target="jscal-prop-icalcomponent">"iCalComponent" property</xref>.</t>
          <t>If the LANGUAGE parameter is set and the DESCRIPTION property is set in a VEVENT or VTODO component, then the parameter value converts to the "locale" property of the Event or Task object, unless the SUMMARY property in the same component has the LANGUAGE parameter set.</t>
          <t>If the LANGUAGE parameter is set and the DESCRIPTION property is set in a VCALENDAR component, then the parameter value converts to the "locale" property of the Group object, unless the NAME property in the same component has the LANGUAGE parameter set.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the DESCRIPTION property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-description">
            <name>Converting the DESCRIPTION property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
DESCRIPTION:Their pancakes are delicious\; they are fluffy and sweet.
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"description": "Their pancakes are delicious; they are fluffy and sweet."
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-dtend">
          <name>DTEND</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.2.2" sectionFormat="parens">DTEND property</xref> in a VEVENT component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.1.2" sectionFormat="parens">"duration" property</xref> of the Event object.
          </t>
          <t>The duration is the timespan between the points in time of the DTSTART and DTEND property values when converted to UTC time.</t>
          <t>If the <xref target="ical-timezone-identifiers">timezone identifier</xref> of the DTEND property differs from that of the DTSTART property, then it converts to the "endTimeZone" property of the Event.</t>
          <t>Implementations <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> preserve the fact that the duration got determined by the DTEND property. How to do this depends on the timezone identifiers of the DTSTART and DTEND properties: If the time zone identifiers are not equal, then the presence of the "endTimeZone" property implies that it converted from the DTEND property. If the time zone identifiers are equal, then implementations <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> set the <xref target="jscal-prop-icalcomponent">"iCalComponent" property</xref> in the Event object and there add an entry for the path "duration" in the "convertedProperties" property. The value <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be an ICalProperty object with the "name" property set to "dtend".</t>
          <t>The following examples illustrate how to convert the DTEND property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-dtend-different-tzid">
            <name>Converting the DTEND property with different timezone</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
DTSTART;TZID=Europe/Berlin:20241017T130000
DTEND;TZID=Asia/Bangkok:20241018T040000
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"start": "2024-10-17T13:00:00",
"timeZone": "Europe/Berlin",
"duration": "PT10H",
"endTimeZone": "Asia/Bangkok"
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-dtend-same-tzid">
            <name>Converting the DTEND property with same timezone</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
DTSTART;TZID=Australia/Melbourne:20241002T130000
DTEND;TZID=Australia/Melbourne:20241002T140000
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"start": "2024-10-02T13:00:00",
"timeZone": "Australia/Melbourne",
"duration": "PT1H",
"iCalComponent": {
  "@type": "ICalComponent",
  "name": "vevent",
  "convertedProperties": {
    "duration": {
      "@type": "ICalProperty",
      "name": "dtend"
    }
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-dtend-date-type">
            <name>Converting the DTEND property with DATE value type</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
DTSTART;VALUE=DATE:20240102
DTEND;VALUE=DATE:20240107
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"start": "2024-01-02T00:00:00",
"timeZone": null,
"duration": "P5D",
"showWithoutTime": true,
"iCalComponent": {
  "@type": "ICalComponent",
  "name": "vevent",
  "convertedProperties": {
    "duration": {
      "@type": "ICalProperty",
      "name": "dtend"
    }
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-dtstamp">
          <name>DTSTAMP</name>
          <t>
              The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.7.2" sectionFormat="parens">DTSTAMP property</xref> in a VEVENT or VTODO component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.6" sectionFormat="parens">"updated" property</xref> of the Event or Task object.</t>
          <t>The following examples illustrate how to convert the DTSTAMP property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-dtstamp-vevent-method">
            <name>Converting the DTSTAMP property in a VEVENT component</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VCALENDAR
METHOD:REPLY
BEGIN:VEVENT
DTSTAMP:20240304T132000Z
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
{
  "@type": "Group",
  "entries": [
    {
      "@type": "Event",
      "method": "reply",
      "updated": "2024-03-04T13:20:00Z",
      "...": ""
    }
  ],
  "...": ""
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-dtstamp-participant">
            <name>Converting the DTSTAMP property in a PARTICIPANT component</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
BEGIN:PARTICIPANT
DTSTAMP:20240304T132000Z
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"participants": {
  "f4": {
    "@type": "Participant",
    "updated": "2024-03-04T13:20:00Z",
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-dtstart">
          <name>DTSTART</name>
          <t>
              The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.2.4" sectionFormat="parens">DTSTART property</xref> in a VEVENT or VTODO component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.7.2" sectionFormat="parens">"start" property</xref> of the Event or Task object.</t>
          <t>See <xref target="convert-date-and-date-time"/> how to convert DATE and DATE-TIME values.</t>
          <t>For VEVENT and VTODO components, the <xref target="ical-timezone-identifiers">timezone identifier</xref> of the DTSTART property converts to the "timeZone" property of the Event or Task object.  In addition, if the value type of the DTSTART property is DATE, then the value of the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.4" sectionFormat="parens">"showWithoutTime" property</xref> is "true".</t>
          <t>The following examples illustrate how to convert the DTSTART property for the VEVENT and VTODO components.</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-dtstart-tzid">
            <name>Converting the DTSTART property with TZID parameter</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
DTSTART;TZID=Europe/Berlin:20240921T105302
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"start": "2024-09-21T10:53:02",
"timeZone": "Europe/Berlin",
"showWithoutTime": false
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-dtstart-utc">
            <name>Converting the DTSTART property with UTC time</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
DTSTART:20240921T105302Z
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"start": "2024-09-21T10:53:02",
"timeZone": "Etc/UTC",
"showWithoutTime": false
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-dtstart-float">
            <name>Converting the DTSTART property with floating time</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
DTSTART:20240921T105302
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"start": "2024-09-21T10:53:02",
"timeZone": null,
"showWithoutTime": false
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-dtstart-date">
            <name>Converting the DTSTART property with value type DATE</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
DTSTART;VALUE=DATE:20240921
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"start": "2024-09-21T00:00:00",
"timeZone": null,
"showWithoutTime": true
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-due">
          <name>DUE</name>
          <t>
              The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.2.3" sectionFormat="parens">DUE property</xref> in a VTODO component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.2.1" sectionFormat="parens">"due" property</xref> of the Task object.</t>
          <t>See <xref target="convert-date-and-date-time"/> how to convert DATE and DATE-TIME values.</t>
          <t>If the VTODO component does not contain a DTSTART property, then the <xref target="ical-timezone-identifiers">timezone identifier</xref> of the DUE property converts to the "timeZone" property of the Task object. If it contains both the DUE and DTSTART properties and the timezone identifier of the DUE property differs from that of the DTSTART property, then the "due" date-time property value <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be relative to the time zone of DTSTART.</t>
          <t>If the value type of the DUE property is DATE, then the value of the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.4" sectionFormat="parens">"showWithoutTime" property</xref> is "true".</t>
          <t>The following examples illustrate how to convert the DUE property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-due-tzid">
            <name>Converting the DUE property with TZID parameter</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VTODO
DUE;TZID=Europe/Berlin:20240921T105302
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"@type": "Task",
"due": "2024-09-21T10:53:02",
"timeZone": "Europe/Berlin",
"showWithoutTime": false
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-due-utc">
            <name>Converting the DUE property with UTC time</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VTODO
DUE:20240921T105302Z
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"@type": "Task",
"due": "2024-09-21T10:53:02",
"timeZone": "Etc/UTC",
"showWithoutTime": false
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-due-float">
            <name>Converting the DUE property with floating time</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VTODO
DUE:20240921T105302
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"@type": "Task",
"due": "2024-09-21T10:53:02",
"timeZone": null,
"showWithoutTime": false
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-due-date">
            <name>Converting the DUE property with value type DATE</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VTODO
DUE;VALUE=DATE:20240921
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"@type": "Task",
"due": "2024-09-21T00:00:00",
"timeZone": null,
"showWithoutTime": true
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-due-and-dtstart-date">
            <name>Converting the DUE property with value type DATE in combination with DTSTART</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VTODO
DTSTART;VALUE=DATE:20250220
DUE;VALUE=DATE:20250221
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"@type": "Task",
"start": "2025-02-20T00:00:00",
"due": "2025-02-21T00:00:00",
"showWithoutTime": true
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-duration">
          <name>DURATION</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.2.5" sectionFormat="parens">DURATION property</xref> in a VEVENT or VTODO component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.1.2" sectionFormat="parens">"duration" property</xref> of the Event or Task object.
          </t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the DURATION property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-duration">
            <name>Converting the DURATION</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
DURATION:PT1H
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"duration": "PT1H"
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-estimated-duration">
          <name>ESTIMATED-DURATION</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="ical-tasks" section="12.1" sectionFormat="parens">ESTIMATED-DURATION property</xref> in a VTODO component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.2.3" sectionFormat="parens">"estimatedDuration" property</xref> of the Task object.
          </t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the ESTIMATED-DURATION property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-estimated-duration">
            <name>Converting the ESTIMATED-DURATION</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VTODO
ESTIMATED-DURATION:P2D
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"@type": "Task",
"estimatedDuration": "P2D"
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-exdate">
          <name>EXDATE</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.5.1" sectionFormat="parens">EXDATE property</xref> in a VEVENT or VTODO component converts to a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="1.4.9" sectionFormat="parens">PatchObject value</xref>.  The converted object is set in the "recurrenceOverrides" property of the Event or Task object.
          </t>
          <t>The property value converts to the key in the "recurrenceOverrides" property value. See <xref target="convert-date-and-date-time"/> how to convert DATE and DATE-TIME values. The date-time <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be relative to the timezone identified by the "timeZone" property of the Event or Task.  The PatchObject value <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> set the "excluded" member to "true" and <bcp14>MUST NOT</bcp14> set any other property.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the EXDATE property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-exdate">
            <name>Converting the EXDATE property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
DTSTART:20230101T130000Z
RRULE:FREQ=MONTHLY
EXDATE:20230801T130000Z
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"start": "2023-01-01T13:00:00",
"timeZone": "Etc/UTC",
"recurrenceRule": {
  "@type": "RecurrenceRule",
  "frequency": "monthly"
},
"recurrenceOverrides": {
  "2023-08-01T13:00:00": {
    "excluded": true
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-geo">
          <name>GEO</name>
          <t>A GEO property with the DERIVED parameter value "TRUE" does not convert to JSCalendar. For non-derived GEO properties, the following rules apply:</t>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.6" sectionFormat="parens">GEO property</xref> in a VEVENT or VTODO component converts to a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="parens">Location object</xref>.  If the VEVENT or VTODO component also contains the <xref target="ical-prop-location">LOCATION property</xref>, then the GEO and LOCATION properties convert to the same Location object.  The converted object is set in the "locations" property of the Event or Task object.
          </t>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.6" sectionFormat="parens">GEO property</xref> in a PARTICIPANT component converts to a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="parens">Location object</xref>.  The converted object is set in the "locations" property of the Participant object.
          </t>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.6" sectionFormat="parens">GEO property</xref> in a VLOCATION component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="parens">"coordinates" property</xref> of the Location object.
          </t>
          <t>The pair of FLOAT values converts to a URI with the <xref target="RFC5870">"geo" scheme</xref>.  The first FLOAT value converts to the "coord-a" part of the URI, the second FLOAT value to the "coord-b" part. A preceding plus sign (+) of the FLOAT value <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be omitted, a preceding minus sign (-) <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be preserved.  The optional "coord-c" part of the URI <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be omitted.</t>
          <t>Implementations <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> preserve the fact that the Location "coordinates" property converted from a GEO property. How to do so depends on how the GEO property converted to a Location object:</t>
          <ul>
            <li>If the GEO property converted from a VLOCATION component, then implementations <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> add a path to the "coordinates" property in the "iCalComponent/convertedProperties" property of the Location object.</li>
            <li>Otherwise, implementations <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> set the "iCalProperty" property of the Location object. Alternatively they <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> add a "iCalComponent" property to the object that contains this Location object in its "locations" property, and point to the "coordinates" property in the "convertedProperties" property.</li>
          </ul>
          <t>The following examples illustrate how to convert the GEO property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-geo">
            <name>Converting the GEO property in a VEVENT</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
GEO:45.5;-93.3
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"locations": {
  "d4": {
    "@type": "Location",
    "coordinates": "geo:45.5,-93.3",
    "iCalProperty": {
      "@type": "ICalProperty",
      "name": "geo"
    },
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-geo-and-location">
            <name>Converting the GEO and LOCATION properties in a VEVENT</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
LOCATION:Taj Mahal
GEO:27.175;78.041944
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"locations": {
  "2": {
    "@type": "Location",
    "name": "Taj Mahal",
    "coordinates": "geo:27.175,78.041944",
    "...": ""
  }
},
"iCalComponent": {
  "@type": "ICalComponent",
  "name": "vevent",
  "convertedProperties": {
    "locations/2/coordinates": {
      "@type": "ICalProperty",
      "name": "geo"
    }
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-geo-vlocation">
            <name>Converting the GEO property in a VLOCATION</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
BEGIN:VLOCATION
NAME:Eiffel Tower
GEO:48.858222;2.2945
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"locations": {
  "2": {
    "@type": "Location",
    "name": "Eiffel Tower",
    "coordinates": "geo:48.858222,2.2945",
    "iCalComponent": {
      "@type": "ICalComponent",
      "name": "vlocation",
      "convertedProperties": {
        "coordinates": {
          "@type": "ICalProperty",
          "name": "geo"
        }
      }
    }
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-image">
          <name>IMAGE</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.10" sectionFormat="parens">IMAGE property</xref> in a VEVENT, VTODO, VLOCATION, PARTICIPANT, or VCALENDAR component converts to a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="1.4.11" sectionFormat="parens">Link object</xref>.  The converted object is set in the "links" property of the Event, Task, Location, Participant, or Group object.
          </t>
          <t>The property value converts to the "href" property of the Link object. A value of type URI converts as-is. See <xref target="ical-prop-attach"/> how to convert a BINARY value. If the DISPLAY parameter is set, then the "rel" property of the Link object <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be set to "icon".</t>
          <t>Its parameters convert as follows:</t>
          <table>
            <name>Parameters of the IMAGE property</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Name</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>Property</th>
                <th>Note</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>DISPLAY</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="6.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>display</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>FMTTYPE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.8" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>contentType</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>LABEL</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="6.4" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>title</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>LINKREL</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9253" section="6.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>rel</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>SIZE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC8607" section="4.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>size</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the IMAGE property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-image">
            <name>Converting the IMAGE property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
IMAGE;VALUE=URI;DISPLAY=BADGE;LABEL=An image;FMTTYPE=image/png:
 https://example.com/images/party.png
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"links": {
  "4": {
    "@type": "Link",
    "href": "https://example.com/images/party.png",
    "display": {
      "badge": "true"
    },
    "rel": "icon",
    "contentType": "image/png",
    "title": "An image"
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-last-modified">
          <name>LAST-MODIFIED</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.7.3" sectionFormat="parens">LAST-MODIFIED property</xref> in a VCALENDAR component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.6" sectionFormat="parens">"updated" property</xref> of the Group object.
          </t>
          <t>
              The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.7.3" sectionFormat="parens">LAST-MODIFIED property</xref> in a VEVENT or VTODO component does <em>not</em> convert to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.6" sectionFormat="parens">"updated" property</xref> of the Event or Task object. Implementations <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> instead preserve the LAST-MODIFIED property in the "iCalComponent" property.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the LAST-MODIFIED property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-last-modified">
            <name>Converting the IMAGE property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VCALENDAR
LAST-MODIFIED:20240914T231257Z
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"@type": "Group",
"updated": "2024-09-14T23:12:57Z"
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-link">
          <name>LINK</name>
          <t>A <xref target="RFC9253" section="8.2" sectionFormat="parens">LINK property</xref> with value type URI in a VEVENT, VTODO, PARTICIPANT, VLOCATION, or VCALENDAR component converts to a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="1.4.11" sectionFormat="parens">Link object</xref>.  The converted object is set in the "links" property of the Event, Task, Participant, Location, or Group object.</t>
          <t>The property value converts to the "href" property of the Link object.</t>
          <t>The LINK property parameters convert as follows:</t>
          <table>
            <name>Parameters of the LINK property</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Name</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>Link Property</th>
                <th>Note</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>FMTTYPE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.8" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>contentType</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>LABEL</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC7986" section="6.4" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>title</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>LINKREL</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC9253" section="6.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>rel</td>
                <td>See remarks below</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>Remarks:</t>
          <ul>
            <li>The LINKREL parameter value is defined to be either an URI or an <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.1" sectionFormat="parens">"iana-token"</xref>. Only parameter values of form "iana-token" convert to the "rel" property of the Link object. The values convert to lowercase.</li>
          </ul>
          <t>A LINK property with any other value type does not convert to a standard JSCalendar element. Implementations <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> convert it to the <xref target="jscal-prop-icalcomponent">"iCalComponent" property</xref>.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the LINK property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-link">
            <name>Converting the LINK property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
LINK;LINKREL=source;LABEL=Venue;VALUE=URI:
 https://example.com/events
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"links": {
  "a": {
    "@type": "Link",
    "href": "https://example.com/events",
    "title": "Venue",
    "rel": "source"
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-location">
          <name>LOCATION</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.7" sectionFormat="parens">LOCATION property</xref> in a VEVENT or VTODO component converts to a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="parens">Location object</xref>, unless its DERIVED parameter value is TRUE. The converted object is set in the "locations" property of the Event or Task. The property value converts to the "title" property of the Location object. If the DERIVED parameter value is TRUE, then the property does not convert to a Location object. Instead, a VLOCATION component is expected to convert to a Location object.</t>
          <t>If the calendar component contains multiple VLOCATION components, then the LOCATION property also converts to the "mainLocationId" property of the Event or Task object. If the LOCATION property is not derived, then the identifier of its Location object is set in the "mainLocationId". If instead the LOCATION property is derived and its property value matches the NAME property value of a VLOCATION component, then the "mainLocationId" property value matches the identifier of the Location object to which that VLOCATION component converts to.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the LOCATION property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-location">
            <name>Converting the LOCATION property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
LOCATION:Conference Room - F123\, Bldg. 002
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"locations": {
  "f45": {
    "@type": "Location",
    "name": "Conference Room - F123, Bldg. 002",
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the LOCATION property and multiple VLOCATION components:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-location-vlocation">
            <name>Converting the LOCATION property and multiple VLOCATION components</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
LOCATION;DERIVED=TRUE:Fred's Bar
BEGIN:VLOCATION
NAME:Fred's Bar
LOCATION-TYPE:bar
...
END:VLOCATION
BEGIN:VLOCATION
NAME:XYZ Parking
LOCATION-TYPE:parking
GEO:40.71427;-74.00597
...
END:VLOCATION
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"locations": {
  "1": {
    "@type": "Location",
    "name": "Fred's Bar",
    "...": ""
  },
  "2": {
    "@type": "Location",
    "name": "XYZ Parking",
    "...": ""
  },
  "mainLocationId": "1"
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-location-type">
          <name>LOCATION-TYPE</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC9073" section="6.1" sectionFormat="parens">LOCATION-TYPE property</xref> in a VLOCATION component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="parens">"locationTypes" property</xref> of the Location object.</t>
          <t>The list of location type values converts to a set of location types. The values convert case-sensitively. All LOCATION-TYPE properties in the same VLOCATION convert to the "locationTypes" property in the Location object.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the LOCATION-TYPE property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-location-type">
            <name>Converting the LOCATION property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
BEGIN:VLOCATION
LOCATION-TYPE:hotel,restaurant
LOCATION-TYPE:bar
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"locations": {
  "1": {
    "@type": "Location",
    "locationTypes": {
      "bar": true,
      "hotel": true,
      "restaurant": true
    },
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-method">
          <name>METHOD</name>
          <t>
              The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.7.2" sectionFormat="parens">METHOD property</xref> in a VCALENDAR component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.8" sectionFormat="parens">"method" property</xref> of all Event or Task objects that are listed in the Group object's entries property.
          </t>
          <t>The property value converts in lowercase.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the METHOD property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-method">
            <name>Converting the METHOD property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VCALENDAR
METHOD:REQUEST
BEGIN:VEVENT
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
{
  "@type": "Group",
  "entries": [
    {
      "@type": "Event",
      "method": "request",
      "...": ""
    }
  ],
  "...": ""
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-name">
          <name>NAME</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.1" sectionFormat="parens">NAME property</xref> in a VLOCATION component converts to the "name" property of the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="parens">Location</xref> or <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="parens">Participant</xref> object.
          </t>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.1" sectionFormat="parens">NAME property</xref> in a VCALENDAR component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.1" sectionFormat="parens">"title" property</xref> of the Group object. If the LANGUAGE parameter is set, then the parameter value converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.9" sectionFormat="parens">"locale" property</xref> of the same object.
          </t>
          <t>The following examples illustrate how to convert the NAME property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-name-vcalendar">
            <name>Converting the NAME property in a VCALENDAR component</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VCALENDAR
NAME;LANGUAGE=de:Feiertage Deutschland 2025
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
{
  "@type": "Group",
  "title": "Feiertage Deutschland 2025",
  "locale": "de",
  "...": ""
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-name-vlocation">
            <name>Converting the NAME property in the VLOCATION component</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
BEGIN:VLOCATION
NAME:Room B
...
END:VLOCATION
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"locations": {
  "1": {
    "@type": "Location",
    "name": "Room B",
    "iCalComponent": {
      "@type": "ICalComponent",
      "name": "vlocation"
    }
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-organizer">
          <name>ORGANIZER</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.3" sectionFormat="parens">ORGANIZER property</xref> in a VEVENT or VTODO component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.4" sectionFormat="parens">"organizerCalendarAddress" property</xref> of the Event or Task object and to a Participant object in the  <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="parens">"participants" property</xref>. The ORGANIZER property value converts to the "calendarAddress" property of the Participant, the "owner" role is set in Participant "roles" property.</t>
          <t>An ORGANIZER property, an ATTENDEE property, and a PARTICIPANT component in the same iCalendar component all convert to the same Participant object, if their converted calendarAddress property values are equal. How to deal with conflicting property values is implementation-specific.</t>
          <t>The ORGANIZER property parameters convert as follows:</t>
          <table>
            <name>Parameters of the ORGANIZER property</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Name</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>Property</th>
                <th>Note</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>CN</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>name</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>DIR</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>links</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>The following examples illustrate how to convert the ORGANIZER property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-organizer">
            <name>Converting an ORGANIZER property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
ORGANIZER:mailto:foo@example.com
ATTENDEE;RSVP=TRUE;PARTSTAT=NEEDS-ACTION:mailto:bar@example.com
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"organizerCalendarAddress": "mailto:foo@example.com",
"participants": {
  "a": {
    "@type": "Participant",
    "calendarAddress": "mailto:foo@example.com",
    "roles": {
      "owner": true
    }
  },
  "b": {
    "@type": "Participant",
    "calendarAddress": "mailto:bar@example.com",
    "expectReply": true,
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-organizer-and-attendee">
            <name>Converting an ORGANIZER and ATTENDEE property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
ORGANIZER:mailto:foo@example.com
ATTENDEE;RSVP=FALSE;PARTSTAT=ACCEPTED;CN=Jane Doe:mailto:foo@example.com
...
ATTENDEE;RSVP=TRUE;PARTSTAT=NEEDS-ACTION:mailto:bar@example.com
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"organizerCalendarAddress": "mailto:foo@example.com",
"participants": {
  "a": {
    "@type": "Participant",
    "calendarAddress": "mailto:foo@example.com",
    "name": "Jane Doe",
    "participationStatus": "accepted",
    "roles": {
      "attendee": true,
      "owner": true
    },
    "expectReply": false
  },
  "b": {
    "@type": "Participant",
    "calendarAddress": "mailto:bar@example.com",
    "expectReply": true,
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-percent-complete">
          <name>PERCENT-COMPLETE</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.8" sectionFormat="parens">PERCENT-COMPLETE property</xref> in a VTODO component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.2.4" sectionFormat="parens">"percentComplete" property</xref> of the Task object.
          </t>
          <t>A Task object which has the "method" property set might represent an iTIP reply of one of the participants in the object. In this case the value of the "percentComplete" property in the Task also converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="parens">percentComplete</xref> of that Participant object, which represents the participant from which the iTIP reply originated.</t>
          <t>The PERCENT-COMPLETE property in a PARTICIPANT component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="parens">"percentComplete" property</xref> of the Participant object.</t>
          <t>The following examples illustrate how to convert the PERCENT-COMPLETE property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-percent-complete-method">
            <name>Converting the PERCENT-COMPLETE property in a VEVENT component</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VCALENDAR
METHOD:REPLY
BEGIN:VTODO
PERCENT-COMPLETE:53
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
{
  "@type": "Group",
  "entries": [
    {
      "@type": "Task",
      "method": "reply",
      "percentComplete": 53,
      "...": ""
    }
  ],
  "...": ""
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-percent-complete-participant">
            <name>Converting the PERCENT-COMPLETE property in a PARTICIPANT component</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VTODO
BEGIN:PARTICIPANT
PERCENT-COMPLETE:78
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"@type": "Task",
"participants": {
  "f4": {
    "@type": "Participant",
    "percentComplete": 78,
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-priority">
          <name>PRIORITY</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.9" sectionFormat="parens">PRIORITY property</xref> in a VEVENT or VTODO component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.1" sectionFormat="parens">"priority" property</xref> of the Event or Task object.
          </t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the PRIORITY property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-priority">
            <name>Converting the PRIORITY property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
PRIORITY:3
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"priority": 3
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-prodid">
          <name>PRODID</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.7.3" sectionFormat="parens">PRODID property</xref> in a VCALENDAR component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.4" sectionFormat="parens">"prodId" property</xref> of the Group object, and to the "prodId" property of all Event or Task objects that are listed in the Group object's entries property.</t>
          <t>The property value converts verbatim.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the PRODID property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-prodid">
            <name>Converting the PRODID property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VCALENDAR
PRODID:-//BAZ//bam//EN
BEGIN:VEVENT
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
{
  "@type": "Group",
  "prodId": "-//BAZ//bam//EN",
  "entries": [
    {
      "@type": "Event",
      "prodId": "-//BAZ//bam//EN",
      "...": ""
    }
  ],
  "...": ""
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-rdate">
          <name>RDATE</name>
          <t>
              A <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.5.2" sectionFormat="parens">RDATE property</xref> with value type DATE or DATE-TIME in a VEVENT or VTODO component converts to a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="1.4.9" sectionFormat="parens">PatchObject value</xref>.  The converted object is set in the "recurrenceOverrides" property of the Event or Task object.
          </t>
          <t>The property value converts to the key in the "recurrenceOverrides" property value. See <xref target="convert-date-and-date-time"/> how to convert DATE and DATE-TIME values. The date-time <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be relative to the timezone identified by the "timeZone" property of the Event or Task object. The PatchObject value <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be an empty JSON object.</t>
          <t>A RDATE property with value type PERIOD does not convert to a standard JSCalendar element.  Implementations <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> convert it to the <xref target="jscal-prop-icalcomponent">"iCalComponent" property</xref> of the Event or Task object.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the RDATE property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-rdate">
            <name>Converting the RDATE property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
DTSTART:20230101T130000Z
RRULE:FREQ=MONTHLY
RDATE:20230805T170000Z
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"start": "2023-01-01T13:00:00",
"timeZone": "Etc/UTC",
"recurrenceRule": {
  "@type": "RecurrenceRule",
  "frequency": "monthly"
},
"recurrenceOverrides": {
  "2023-08-05T17:00:00": {}
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-recurrence-id">
          <name>RECURRENCE-ID</name>
          <t>The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.4" sectionFormat="parens">RECURRENCE-ID property</xref> in a VEVENT or VTODO component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.3.1" sectionFormat="parens">"recurrenceId" property</xref> of the Event or Task object. The <xref target="ical-timezone-identifiers">timezone identifier</xref> of the RECURRENCE-ID property converts to the "recurrenceIdTimeZone" property.</t>
          <t>See <xref target="convert-date-and-date-time"/> how to convert DATE and DATE-TIME values.</t>
          <t>The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.13" sectionFormat="parens">RANGE parameter</xref> does not convert to a standard JSCalendar element. Implementations <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> preserve it in the <xref target="jscal-prop-icalcomponent">iCalComponent</xref> property.</t>
          <t>See <xref target="ical-recurring-components"/> for further requirements and examples.</t>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-related-to">
          <name>RELATED-TO</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.5" sectionFormat="parens">RELATED-TO property</xref> in a VEVENT, VTODO, or VALARM component converts to a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="1.4.10" sectionFormat="parens">Relation object</xref>.  The converted object is set in the "relatedTo" property of the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.3" sectionFormat="parens">Event or Task object</xref>, or the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.5.2" sectionFormat="parens">Alert object</xref>.
          </t>
          <t>The property value in a VEVENT or VTODO converts as-is to the id of the Relation object in the "relatedTo" property. The property value in a VALARM converts to the same value as the id of that Alert object, which represents the VALARM component having that property value set in the UID property. Any RELTYPE parameters convert to the "relations" property in that Relation object. The parameter values convert in lowercase.</t>
          <t>The following examples illustrate how to convert the RELATED-TO property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-related-to">
            <name>Converting the RELATED-TO property in a VEVENT</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
RELATED-TO;RELTYPE=PARENT:4E05861C-A0C9-46AC-9A66-760FC1E0E167
RELATED-TO:4120A9B1-1133-4AC0-9185-C4C8396048ED
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"relatedTo": {
  "4E05861C-A0C9-46AC-9A66-760FC1E0E167": {
    "@type": "Relation",
    "relation": {
      "parent": true
    }
  },
  "4120A9B1-1133-4AC0-9185-C4C8396048ED": {
    "@type": "Relation"
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-related-to-valarm">
            <name>Converting the RELATED-TO property in a VALARM</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
...
BEGIN:VALARM
UID:8297C37D-BA2D-4476-91AE-C1EAA364F8E1
JSID:alert1
TRIGGER:-PT15M
DESCRIPTION:Event reminder
ACTION:DISPLAY
ACKNOWLEDGED:20210302T151514Z
END:VALARM
...
BEGIN:VALARM
UID:DE7B5C34-83FF-47FE-BE9E-FF41AE6DD097
JSID:alert2
TRIGGER;VALUE=DATE-TIME:20210302T152000Z
RELATED-TO;RELTYPE=SNOOZE:8297C37D-BA2D-4476-91AE-C1EAA364F8E1
DESCRIPTION:Event reminder
ACTION:DISPLAY
END:VALARM
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"alerts": {
  "alert1": {
    "@type": "Alert",
    "trigger": {
      "@type": "OffsetTrigger",
      "offset": "-PT15M"
    },
    "...": ""
  },
  "alert2": {
    "@type": "Alert",
    "trigger": {
      "@type": "AbsoluteTrigger",
      "when": "2021-03-02T15:20:00Z"
    },
    "relatedTo": {
      "alert1": {
        "@type": "Relation",
        "relation": {
          "snooze": true
        }
      }
    },
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-rrule">
          <name>RRULE</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.5.3" sectionFormat="parens">RRULE property</xref> in a VEVENT or VTODO component converts to a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.3.3" sectionFormat="parens">RecurrenceRule object</xref>.  The converted object is set in the "recurrenceRule" property of the Event or Task object.
          </t>
          <t>The RECUR value type converts to a RecurrenceRule object as follows:</t>
          <table>
            <name>Converting the RECUR value type to a RecurrenceRule object</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>RRULE field</th>
                <th>RecurrenceRule property</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>FREQ</td>
                <td>frequency</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>UNTIL</td>
                <td>until</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>COUNT</td>
                <td>count</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>INTERVAL</td>
                <td>interval</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>BYSECOND</td>
                <td>bySecond</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>BYMINUTE</td>
                <td>byMinute</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>BYHOUR</td>
                <td>byHour</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>BYDAY</td>
                <td>byDay</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>BYMONTHDAY</td>
                <td>byMonthDay</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>BYYEARDAY</td>
                <td>byYearDay</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>BYWEEKNO</td>
                <td>byWeekNo</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>BYMONTH</td>
                <td>byMonth</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>BYSETPOS</td>
                <td>bySetPosition</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>WKST</td>
                <td>firstDayOfWeek</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>RSCALE <xref target="RFC7529"/>
                </td>
                <td>rscale</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>SKIP <xref target="RFC7529"/>
                </td>
                <td>skip</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>The string values of the FREQ, WKST, RSCALE convert to lowercase.  The UNTIL part in a VEVENT or VTODO converts to a LocalDateTime value relative to the timezone of the Event or Task object.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the RRULE property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-rrule">
            <name>Example for converting the RRULE property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
DTSTART;TZID=Europe/Berlin:20240101T010000
RRULE:FREQ=YEARLY
 ;INTERVAL=2
 ;BYMONTH=1
 ;BYDAY=SU
 ;BYHOUR=8,9
 ;BYMINUTE=30
 ;UNTIL=20240930T120000Z
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"recurrenceRule": {
  "@type": "RecurrenceRule",
  "frequency": "yearly",
  "interval": 2,
  "byMonth": [
    "1"
  ],
  "byDay": [
    {
      "@type": "NDay",
      "day": "su"
    }
  ],
  "byHour": [
    8,
    9
  ],
  "byMinute": [
    30
  ],
  "until": "2024-09-30T14:00:00"
},
"start": "2024-01-01T01:00:00",
"timeZone": "Europe/Berlin"
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-sequence">
          <name>SEQUENCE</name>
          <t>The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.7.4" sectionFormat="parens">SEQUENCE property</xref> in a VEVENT or VTODO component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.7" sectionFormat="parens">"sequence" property</xref> of the Event or Task object.</t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the SEQUENCE property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-sequence">
            <name>Example for converting the SEQUENCE property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
SEQUENCE:3
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"sequence": 3
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-status">
          <name>STATUS</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.11" sectionFormat="parens">STATUS property</xref> in a VEVENT component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.1.3" sectionFormat="parens">"status" property</xref> of the Event object.

            The STATUS property in a VTODO component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.2.5" sectionFormat="parens">"progress" property</xref> of the Task object.
          </t>
          <t>The property value converts in lowercase.</t>
          <t>The following examples illustrate how to convert the STATUS property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-status-vevent">
            <name>Example for converting the STATUS property in a VEVENT component</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
STATUS:TENTATIVE
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"status": "tentative"
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-status-vtodo">
            <name>Example for converting the STATUS property in a VTODO component</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VTODO
STATUS:IN-PROCESS
...
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
{
  "@type": "Task",
  "progress": "in-process",
  "...": ""
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-source">
          <name>SOURCE</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.8" sectionFormat="parens">SOURCE property</xref> in a VCALENDAR component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.3.2" sectionFormat="parens">"source" property</xref> of the Group object.
          </t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the SOURCE property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-source">
            <name>Example for converting the SOURCE property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VCALENDAR
SOURCE;VALUE=URI:https://example.com/holidays.ics
...
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
{
  "@type": "Group",
  "source": "https://example.com/holidays.ics",
  "...": ""
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-styled-description">
          <name>STYLED-DESCRIPTION</name>
          <t>The <xref target="RFC9073" section="6.5" sectionFormat="parens">STYLED-DESCRIPTION property</xref> in a PARTICIPANT, VLOCATION, VEVENT or VTODO component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.2" sectionFormat="parens">"description" property</xref> of the Participant, Location, Event or Task object under the following conditions:</t>
          <ul>
            <li>The property value type <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be TEXT.</li>
            <li>The FMTTYPE parameter either <bcp14>MUST NOT</bcp14> be set, or its value <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be a <xref target="RFC6838">media type</xref> with top-level type "text".</li>
            <li>Its DERIVED parameter value <bcp14>MUST NOT</bcp14> be TRUE. If the value is TRUE, then another property in the same component is expected to contain the description.</li>
          </ul>
          <t>If these conditions are not met, implementations MAY preserve the property in the <xref target="jscal-prop-icalcomponent">"iCalComponent" property</xref>.</t>
          <t>If the LANGUAGE parameter is set and the STYLED-DESCRIPTION property is set in a VEVENT or VTODO component, then the parameter value converts to the "locale" property of the Event or Task object, unless the SUMMARY or DESCRIPTION properties in the same component have the LANGUAGE parameter set.</t>
          <t>Its parameters convert as follows:</t>
          <table>
            <name>Parameters of the STYLED-DESCRIPTION property</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Name</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>Property</th>
                <th>Note</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>FMTTYPE</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.8" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>descriptionContentType</td>
                <td/>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the STYLED-DESCRIPTION property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-styled-description">
            <name>Converting the STYLED-DESCRIPTION property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
STYLED-DESCRIPTION;VALUE=TEXT;FMTTYPE=text/html:
 <!DOCTYPE html><html><body>hello\,<b>world</b></body></html>
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"description": "<!DOCTYPE html><html><body>hello,<b>world</b></body></html>",
"descriptionContentType": "text/html"
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-summary">
          <name>SUMMARY</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.12" sectionFormat="parens">SUMMARY property</xref> in a VEVENT or VTODO component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.1" sectionFormat="parens">"title" property</xref> of the Event or Task object. If the LANGUAGE parameter is set, then the parameter value converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.9" sectionFormat="parens">"locale" property</xref> of the same object.
          </t>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.12" sectionFormat="parens">SUMMARY property</xref> in a PARTICIPANT component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="parens">"name" property</xref>.
          </t>
          <t>The following examples illustrate how to convert the SUMMARY property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-summary">
            <name>Converting the SUMMARY property in a VEVENT</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
SUMMARY:Birthday Party
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"title": "Birthday Party"
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-summary-language">
            <name>Converting the SUMMARY property with LANGUAGE parameter in a VEVENT</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
SUMMARY;LANGUAGE=fr:Fête d'anniversaire
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"title": "Fête d'anniversaire",
"locale": "fr",
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-summary-participant">
            <name>Converting the SUMMARY property in a PARTICIPANT</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
BEGIN:PARTICIPANT
SUMMARY:John
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"participants": {
  "1": {
    "@type": "Participant",
    "name": "John",
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-transp">
          <name>TRANSP</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.2.7" sectionFormat="parens">TRANSP property</xref> in a VEVENT or VTODO component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.2" sectionFormat="parens">"freeBusyStatus" property</xref> of the Event or Task object.
          </t>
          <t>Its values convert as follows:</t>
          <table anchor="ical-prop-transp-values">
            <name>Values of the TRANSP property</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>iCalendar value</th>
                <th>JSCalendar value</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>OPAQUE</td>
                <td>busy</td>
              </tr>
              <tr>
                <td>TRANSPARENT</td>
                <td>free</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the TRANSP property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-transp">
            <name>Converting the TRANSP property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
TRANSP:TRANSPARENT
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"freeBusyStatus": "free"
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-trigger">
          <name>TRIGGER</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.6.3" sectionFormat="parens">TRIGGER property</xref> in a VALARM component converts to either an AbsoluteTrigger or OffsetTrigger object.  The converted object is set in the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.5.2" sectionFormat="parens">"trigger" property</xref> of the Alert object.
          </t>
          <t>A property of value type DURATION converts an OffsetTrigger object. The property value converts to its offset property. A value of type DATE-TIME converts to an AbsoluteTrigger object. The property value converts to its when property.</t>
          <t>Its parameters convert as follows:</t>
          <table>
            <name>Parameters of the TRIGGER property</name>
            <thead>
              <tr>
                <th>Name</th>
                <th>Reference</th>
                <th>Property</th>
                <th>Note</th>
              </tr>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <tr>
                <td>RELATED</td>
                <td>
                  <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.14" sectionFormat="comma"/>
                </td>
                <td>relativeTo</td>
                <td>If VALUE=DURATION</td>
              </tr>
            </tbody>
          </table>
          <t>The following examples illustrate how to convert the TRIGGER property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-trigger-offset">
            <name>Converting the TRIGGER property to an OffsetTrigger</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
...
BEGIN:VALARM
TRIGGER;RELATED=END:PT5M
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"alerts": {
  "2d": {
    "@type": "Alert",
    "trigger": {
      "@type": "OffsetTrigger",
      "offset": "PT5M",
      "relativeTo": "end"
    },
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-trigger-absolute">
            <name>Converting the TRIGGER property to an AbsoluteTrigger</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
...
BEGIN:VALARM
TRIGGER;VALUE=DATE-TIME:20250302T010203Z
...
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"alerts": {
  "14": {
    "@type": "Alert",
    "trigger": {
      "@type": "AbsoluteTrigger",
      "when": "2025-03-02T01:02:03Z"
    },
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-uid">
          <name>UID</name>
          <t>
            The <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.7" sectionFormat="parens">UID property</xref> in a VEVENT, VTODO, or VCALENDAR component converts to the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.2" sectionFormat="parens">"uid" property</xref> of the Event, Task, or Group object.
          </t>
          <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the UID property:</t>
          <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-uid">
            <name>Converting the UID property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
UID:5ACEA86F-40CF-47EE-9CCA-7C85588A589F
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"uid": "5ACEA86F-40CF-47EE-9CCA-7C85588A589F"
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section anchor="jscal-to-icalendar">
      <name>Converting JSCalendar to iCalendar</name>
      <section anchor="jscal-alert">
        <name>Alert</name>
        <t>The <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.5.2" sectionFormat="parens">Alert object</xref> converts to a <xref target="ical-comp-valarm">VALARM component</xref>.  Its properties convert as follows:</t>
        <table>
          <name>Properties of the Alert object</name>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Name</th>
              <th>Reference</th>
              <th>Property (or other)</th>
              <th>See</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>acknowledged</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.5.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>ACKNOWLEDGED</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-acknowledged"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>action</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.5.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>ACTION</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-action"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>relatedTo</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>RELATED-TO</td>
              <td>
                <t><xref target="ical-prop-related-to"/>, and remarks below</t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>trigger</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.5.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>TRIGGER</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-trigger"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <t>Remarks:</t>
        <ul>
          <li>
            <t>The value of the RELATED-TO property is the UID property value of that VALARM component, to which the related  Alert object converts to. Consequently, the UID property for such a VALARM <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be set, otherwise the UID property <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> be set.</t>
          </li>
        </ul>
        <t>Other properties <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> be converted to <xref target="ical-prop-jsprop">JSPROP properties</xref> in the VALARM component.</t>
      </section>
      <section anchor="jscal-event-and-task">
        <name>Event and Task</name>
        <t>The <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="2.1" sectionFormat="parens">Event object</xref> converts to a <xref target="ical-comp-vevent">VEVENT component</xref>, the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="2.2" sectionFormat="parens">Task object</xref> converts to a <xref target="ical-comp-vtodo">VTODO component</xref>.</t>
        <t>
            The following table defines how to convert properties that are common to both the Event and Task object types. <xref target="jscal-event-props"/> and <xref target="jscal-task-props"/> later in this section define how to convert properties specific to either Event or Task objects.</t>
        <table anchor="jscal-event-and-task-props">
          <name>Properties of the Event and Task object</name>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Name</th>
              <th>Reference</th>
              <th>Property (or other)</th>
              <th>See</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>alerts</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.5.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>VALARM (component)</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscal-alert">Alert object</xref>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>categories</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.10" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>CONCEPT</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-concept"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>color</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.11" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>COLOR</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-color"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>created</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>CREATED</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-created"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>description</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>DESCRIPTION, or STYLED-DESCRIPTION</td>
              <td>
                <t><xref target="ical-prop-description"/>, <xref target="ical-prop-styled-description"/>, and remarks below</t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>descriptionContentType</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>FMTTYPE (parameter) of STYLED-DESCRIPTION</td>
              <td>
                <t><xref target="ical-prop-styled-description"/>, and remarks below</t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>freeBusyStatus</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>TRANSP</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-transp"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>keywords</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.9" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>CATEGORIES</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-categories"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>links</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.7" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>ATTACH, or other</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="jscal-link">Link object</xref>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>locale</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.9" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>LANGUAGE (parameter) of either SUMMARY, or DESCRIPTION, or STYLED-DESCRIPTION (in order of preference)</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-summary"/>, <xref target="ical-prop-description"/>, <xref target="ical-prop-styled-description"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>locations</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>LOCATION, GEO, or VLOCATION (component)</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="jscal-location">Location object</xref>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>mainLocationId</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>LOCATION</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="jscal-location">Location object</xref>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>method</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.8" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>METHOD of iCalendar object</td>
              <td>
                <t><xref target="ical-prop-method"/>, and <xref target="jscal-group">Group object</xref></t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>organizerCalendarAddress</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.4" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>ORGANIZER</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-organizer"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>participants</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>ATTENDEE, or PARTICIPANT (component)</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="jscal-participant">Participant object</xref>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>priority</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>PRIORITY</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-priority"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>privacy</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>CLASS</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-class"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>prodId</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.4" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>PRODID of iCalendar object</td>
              <td>
                <t><xref target="ical-prop-prodid"/>, and <xref target="jscal-group">Group object</xref></t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>recurrenceId</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.3.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>RECURRENCE-ID</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-recurrence-id"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>recurrenceIdTimeZone</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.3.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>TZID (parameter) of RECURRENCE-ID</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-recurrence-id"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>recurrenceOverrides</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.3.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>RDATE, EXDATE or recurrence override component</td>
              <td><xref target="ical-recurring-components"/>, and remarks below</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>recurrenceRule</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.3.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>RRULE</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-rrule"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>relatedTo</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>RELATED-TO</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-related-to"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>sequence</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.7" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>SEQUENCE</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-sequence"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>start</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.7.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>DTSTART</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-dtstart"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>timeZone</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.7.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>TZID (parameter) of DTSTART and DUE</td>
              <td>
                <t><xref target="ical-prop-dtstart"/>, <xref target="ical-prop-due"/></t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>title</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>SUMMARY</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-summary"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>uid</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>UID</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-uid"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>updated</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>DTSTAMP, and LAST-MODIFIED</td>
              <td>
                <t><xref target="ical-prop-dtstamp"/>, <xref target="ical-prop-last-modified"/></t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>virtualLocations</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>CONFERENCE</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-conference"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <t>Remarks:</t>
        <ul>
          <li>
            <t>The descriptionContentType property value determines if the "description" property converts to the DESCRIPTION or STYLED-DESCRIPTION property. A description of content type "text/plain" converts to the DESCRIPTION property. Any other description converts to the STYLED-DESCRIPTION property, in which case a plain text version of the rich-text description <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> be set additionally in the DESCRIPTION property, having its DERIVED parameter set to "TRUE". How to derive plain text from rich-text is implementation-specific.</t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>The entries in the "recurrenceOverrides" property convert depending on the contents of the PatchObject value. A PatchObject that sets the "excluded" member to "true" converts to an EXDATE property for the date-time of that recurrence instance. An empty PatchObject converts to an RDATE property. Any other PatchObject converts to a recurrence override component in the embedding VCALENDAR component.</t>
          </li>
        </ul>
        <t>Properties specific to the Event object type convert to iCalendar properties as follows:</t>
        <table anchor="jscal-event-props">
          <name>Properties of the Event object</name>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Name</th>
              <th>Reference</th>
              <th>Property (or other)</th>
              <th>See</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>duration</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.1.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>DURATION, or DTEND</td>
              <td>
                <t><xref target="ical-prop-duration"/>, <xref target="ical-prop-dtend"/></t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>endTimeZone</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.1.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>TZID parameter of DTEND</td>
              <td>
                <t><xref target="ical-prop-dtend"/>, <xref target="ical-prop-due"/></t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>status</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.1.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>STATUS</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-status"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <t>Properties specific to the Task object type convert to iCalendar properties as follows:</t>
        <table anchor="jscal-task-props">
          <name>Properties of the Task object</name>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Name</th>
              <th>Reference</th>
              <th>Property (or other)</th>
              <th>See</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>due</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.2.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>DUE</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-due"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>estimatedDuration</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.2.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>ESTIMATED-DURATION</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-estimated-duration"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>percentComplete</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.2.4" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>PERCENT-COMPLETE</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-percent-complete"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>progress</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.2.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>STATUS</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-status"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <t>Other properties <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> be converted to <xref target="ical-prop-jsprop">JSPROP properties</xref> in the VEVENT or VTODO component.</t>
      </section>
      <section anchor="jscal-group">
        <name>Group</name>
        <t>The <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="2.3" sectionFormat="parens">Group object</xref> converts to a <xref target="ical-comp-vcalendar">VCALENDAR component</xref>.  Its properties convert as follows:</t>
        <table>
          <name>Properties of the Group object</name>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Name</th>
              <th>Reference</th>
              <th>Property (or other)</th>
              <th>See</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>categories</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.10" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>CONCEPT</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-concept"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>color</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.11" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>COLOR</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-color"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>created</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>CREATED</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-created"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>entries</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.3.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>VEVENT or VTODO (component)</td>
              <td>
                <t><xref target="jscal-event-and-task">Event and Task object</xref>, and remarks below</t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>keywords</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.9" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>CATEGORIES</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-categories"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>links</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.7" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>ATTACH, or other</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="jscal-link">Link object</xref>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>locale</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.9" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>LANGUAGE (parameter) of either NAME, or DESCRIPTION (in order of preference)</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-name"/>, <xref target="ical-prop-description"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>prodId</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.4" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>PRODID</td>
              <td>
                <t><xref target="ical-prop-prodid"/>, and remarks below</t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>source</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.3.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>SOURCE</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-source"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>title</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.1" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>NAME</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-name"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>uid</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.2" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>UID</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-uid"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>updated</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.1.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>LAST-MODIFIED</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-last-modified"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <t>Remarks:</t>
        <ul>
          <li>
            <t>The prodId property value of the Group object is expected to be equal to the "prodId" property value of all the Group entries. They all convert to the same, single PRODID property in the VCALENDAR component. How to convert unequal prodId property values is implementation-specific. </t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>The method property value in all the Group entries is expected to be equal. How to convert entries with unequal method property values is implementation-specific.</t>
          </li>
        </ul>
        <t>Other properties <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> be converted to <xref target="ical-prop-jsprop">JSPROP properties</xref> in the VCALENDAR component.</t>
      </section>
      <section anchor="jscal-link">
        <name>Link</name>
        <t>The <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="1.4.11" sectionFormat="parens">Link object</xref> converts either an <xref target="ical-prop-attach">ATTACH property</xref> or an <xref target="ical-prop-image">IMAGE property</xref>. Which iCalendar property to choose is implementation-specific. As a guideline:</t>
        <ul>
          <li>Choose the iCalendar property name indicated in the Link object's <xref target="jscal-prop-icalproperty">iCalProperty</xref> property, if set.</li>
          <li>Choose IMAGE, if the "rel" property value is "icon".</li>
          <li> Choose LINK, if the "rel" property is set to any value other than "icon".</li>
          <li>Choose ATTACH otherwise.</li>
        </ul>
        <t>The href property converts to the "iCalendar" property value. The other Link properties convert as follows:</t>
        <table>
          <name>Properties of the Link object</name>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Name</th>
              <th>Reference</th>
              <th>Parameter (or other)</th>
              <th>See</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>contentType</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="1.4.11" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>FMTTYPE</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-attach"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>display</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="1.4.11" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>DISPLAY</td>
              <td><xref target="ical-prop-image"/>, and remarks below
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>rel</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="1.4.11" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>LINKREL</td>
              <td><xref target="RFC9253" section="6.1"/>, and remarks below</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>size</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="1.4.11" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>SIZE</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-attach"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>title</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="RFC7986" section="6.4" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>LABEL</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-attach"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <t>Remarks:</t>
        <ul>
          <li>The LINKREL parameter <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be omitted if the Link object converts to an IMAGE property and the "rel" property value is "icon".</li>
        </ul>
        <t>Other properties <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> be converted to <xref target="ical-prop-jsprop">JSPROP properties</xref> in the same component to which the Link object converts to as a property.</t>
      </section>
      <section anchor="jscal-location">
        <name>Location</name>
        <t>The <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="parens">Location object</xref> converts to either a <xref target="ical-prop-location">LOCATION</xref>, <xref target="ical-prop-geo">GEO</xref>, or <xref target="ical-prop-geo">DTEND</xref> property, or it converts to a <xref target="ical-comp-vlocation">VLOCATION component</xref>. Which iCalendar element to choose is implementation-specific. As a guideline:</t>
        <ul>
          <li>If the "iCalProperty" or "iCalComponent" property on the Location object is set, or the parent JSCalendar object contains an entry for that Location in the "convertedProperties" property of its "iCalComponent" property, then convert the object back to the named iCalendar element.</li>
          <li>Choose LOCATION if the key of the Location object in the "locations" property matches the "mainLocationId" property, or if the "name" property is set and the iCalendar component does not already contain a LOCATION property. The "name" property converts to the LOCATION property value.</li>
          <li>Choose the VLOCATION component otherwise.</li>
        </ul>
        <t>Implementations <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> convert one of the Location objects to both a VLOCATION component and the LOCATION and GEO properties of the component that contains the VLOCATION component. In this case, the DERIVED parameter <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be set on the LOCATION and GEO properties with value "TRUE".</t>
        <t>The properties convert to a VLOCATION component as follows:</t>
        <table>
          <name>Properties of the Location object</name>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Name</th>
              <th>Reference</th>
              <th>Property (or other)</th>
              <th>See</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>coordinates</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>COORDINATES</td>
              <td><xref target="ical-prop-coordinates"/>, <xref target="ical-prop-geo"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>description</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>DESCRIPTION, or STYLED-DESCRIPTION</td>
              <td>
                <t><xref target="ical-prop-description"/>, <xref target="ical-prop-styled-description"/></t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>descriptionContentType</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>FMTTYPE (parameter) of STYLED-DESCRIPTION</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-styled-description"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>links</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.7" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>ATTACH, or other</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="jscal-link">Link object</xref>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>locationTypes</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>LOCATION-TYPE</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-location-type"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>name</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>NAME</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-name"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <t>Other properties <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> be converted to <xref target="ical-prop-jsprop">JSPROP properties</xref> in the VLOCATION component, or the component which the Location converts to as a property.</t>
      </section>
      <section anchor="jscal-participant">
        <name>Participant</name>
        <t>The <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="parens">Participant object</xref> converts to both an <xref target="ical-prop-attendee">ATTENDEE property</xref> and a <xref target="ical-comp-participant">PARTICIPANT component</xref>:</t>
        <ul>
          <li>
            <t>It converts to an ATTENDEE property if the <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="parens">calendarAddress</xref> property is set.</t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>It converts to a PARTICIPANT component if any of the Participant properties in <xref target="jscal-participant-props-participant"/> are set. If the Participant object also converts to an ATTENDEE property, then the CALENDAR-ADDRESS property value of the PARTICIPANT component <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> match the ATTENDEE property value.</t>
          </li>
        </ul>
        <t>The following Participant properties convert to the ATTENDEE property. How to convert these properties if the Participant does not convert to an ATTENDEE is implementation-specific.</t>
        <table anchor="jscal-participant-props-attendee">
          <name>Properties of the Participant object that convert to the ATTENDEE property</name>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Name</th>
              <th>Reference</th>
              <th>Parameter (or other)</th>
              <th>See</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>calendarAddress</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>ATTENDEE</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-attendee"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>delegatedFrom</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>DELEGATED-FROM</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-attendee"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>delegatedTo</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>DELEGATED-TO</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-attendee"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>email</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>EMAIL</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-attendee"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>expectReply</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>RSVP</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-attendee"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>kind</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>CUTYPE</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-attendee"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>memberOf</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>MEMBER</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-attendee"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>name</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>CN</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-attendee"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>participationStatus</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>PARTSTAT</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-attendee"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>progress</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.2.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>PARTSTAT</td>
              <td><xref target="ical-prop-attendee"/>, and remarks below
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>roles</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>ROLE</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-attendee"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>sentBy</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>SENT-BY</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-attendee"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <t>Remarks:</t>
        <ul>
          <li>
            <t>The "attendee" role does not convert to the ROLE parameter: it either is implied if the Participant object converts to an ATTENDEE, otherwise implementations <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> preserve it using the <xref target="ical-prop-jsprop">JSPROP</xref> property. The "owner" role does not convert to any standard iCalendar element: it either is implied if the property value of the ATTENDEE is equal to the value of the ORGANIZER property in the same component, otherwise implementations <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> preserve it using the <xref target="ical-prop-jsprop">JSPROP</xref> property.</t>
          </li>
          <li>
            <t>The progress property converts to the PARTSTAT parameter as outlined in <xref target="ical-prop-attendee-param-partstat"/>.</t>
          </li>
        </ul>
        <t>The following Participant properties convert to the PARTICIPANT component:</t>
        <table anchor="jscal-participant-props-participant">
          <name>Properties of the Participant object that convert to the PARTICIPANT component</name>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Name</th>
              <th>Reference</th>
              <th>Property (or other)</th>
              <th>See</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>description</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>DESCRIPTION, or STYLED-DESCRIPTION</td>
              <td>
                <t><xref target="ical-prop-description"/>, <xref target="ical-prop-styled-description"/>, and remarks below</t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>descriptionContentType</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.4.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>FMTTYPE (parameter) of STYLED-DESCRIPTION</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-styled-description"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>links</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.7" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>ATTACH, or other</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="jscal-link">Link object</xref>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>name</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>NAME</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-name"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>percentComplete</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="5.2.4" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>PERCENT-COMPLETE</td>
              <td>
                <t>
                  <xref target="ical-prop-percent-complete"/>
                </t>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <t>Other properties <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> be converted to <xref target="ical-prop-jsprop">JSPROP properties</xref> in the PARTICIPANT component, or the component which the Participant converts to as a property.</t>
      </section>
      <section anchor="jscal-virtual-location">
        <name>VirtualLocation</name>
        <t>The <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.6" sectionFormat="parens">VirtualLocation object</xref> converts to a <xref target="ical-prop-conference">CONFERENCE property</xref>. If the "description" property is set, then it also converts to a <xref target="ical-comp-vconference">VCONFERENCE component</xref>.</t>
        <t>The "uri" property converts to the CONFERENCE property value. If the VirtualLocation object converts to a VCONFERENCE component, then the "uri" property also converts to the URI property of the VCONFERENCE component.</t>
        <t>The following properties convert to parameters of the CONFERENCE property:</t>
        <table>
          <name>Properties of the VirtualLocation object</name>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Name</th>
              <th>Reference</th>
              <th>Parameter (or other)</th>
              <th>See</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>features</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.6" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>FEATURE</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-conference"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>name</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.5" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>LABEL</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-conference"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <t>The following properties convert to properties of the VCONFERENCE component:</t>
        <table>
          <name>Properties of the VirtualLocation object</name>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th>Name</th>
              <th>Reference</th>
              <th>Property (or other)</th>
              <th>See</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td>description</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.7" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>DESCRIPTION, or STYLED-DESCRIPTION</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-description"/>, <xref target="ical-prop-styled-description"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td>descriptionContenType</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.7" sectionFormat="comma"/>
              </td>
              <td>FMTTYPE (parameter) of STYLED-DESCRIPTION</td>
              <td>
                <xref target="ical-prop-styled-description"/>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <t>Other properties <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> be converted to <xref target="ical-prop-jsprop">JSPROP properties</xref> of the VCONFERENCE component.</t>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section anchor="updates-icalendar">
      <name>Updates to iCalendar</name>
      <section anchor="new-icalendar-properties">
        <name>New Properties</name>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-jsid">
          <name>JSID</name>
          <dl newline="true">
            <dt>Property Name:</dt>
            <dd>JSID</dd>
            <dt>Purpose:</dt>
            <dd>This property preserves the identifier of a JSCalendar object value in iCalendar.</dd>
            <dt>Value type:</dt>
            <dd>TEXT; also see "Format Definition" below for value restrictions.</dd>
            <dt>Property Parameters:</dt>
            <dd>
              IANA and non-standard property parameters can be specified on this property.
        </dd>
            <dt>Conformance:</dt>
            <dd>This property can be specified at most once in any calendar component.</dd>
            <dt>Description:</dt>
            <dd>
              <t>This property specifies the JSON object key of the JSCalendar object to which an iCalendar component converts to. For example, this property set in a VALARM component within a VEVENT component defines the key of the Alert object value in the Event object's "alerts" property (see <xref target="test-ical-prop-jsid-alert"/>).</t>
              <t>The value of the JSID property <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be a valid object key according to the definition of the JSCalendar property to which the component converts to.</t>
            </dd>
            <dt>Format Definition:</dt>
            <dd>
              <t>This property is defined by the following notation:</t>
              <sourcecode type="abnf"><![CDATA[
jsid-prop = "JSID" *(";" other-param) ":" TEXT CRLF
]]></sourcecode>
            </dd>
            <dt anchor="ical-prop-jsid-examples">Example(s):</dt>
            <dd>
              <t>The following example illustrates how to convert the JSID property set in a VALARM component.</t>
              <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-jsid-alert">
                <name>Converting the JSID property of a VALARM component</name>
                <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
...
BEGIN:VALARM
JSID:myalert1
...
END:VALARM
]]></sourcecode>
                <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"@type": "Event",
"alerts": {
  "myalert1": {
    "@type": "Alert",
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
              </figure>
            </dd>
          </dl>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-prop-jsprop">
          <name>JSPROP</name>
          <dl newline="true">
            <dt>Property Name:</dt>
            <dd>JSPROP</dd>
            <dt>Purpose:</dt>
            <dd>This property represents a JSCalendar property in iCalendar.</dd>
            <dt>Value type:</dt>
            <dd>TEXT; also see "Format Definition" below for value restrictions.</dd>
            <dt>Property Parameters:</dt>
            <dd>
              The <xref target="ical-param-jsptr">JSPTR parameter</xref>
              <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be specified on this property. Other IANA and non-standard property parameters can be specified on this property.
        </dd>
            <dt>Conformance:</dt>
            <dd>This property can be specified multiple times in any calendar component.</dd>
            <dt>Description:</dt>
            <dd>
              <t>This property converts an arbitrary JSCalendar property from and to iCalendar.  The iCalendar property value is the JSON-encoded value of the JSCalendar property, represented as a TEXT value.  The JSON value <bcp14>MUST NOT</bcp14> be the null value, and it <bcp14>SHOULD NOT</bcp14> contain insignificant whitespace as defined in <xref target="RFC8259" format="default" sectionFormat="of" derivedContent="RFC8259" section="2"/>.  The value of the JSPTR parameter points to the JSCalendar property within the JSCalendar object.</t>
              <t>The root of the JSON pointer is always the JSCalendar object to which the calendar component converts to, even if the JSON pointer starts with the SOLIDUS (U+002F) character.  The pointer <bcp14>MUST NOT</bcp14> reference into an array.</t>
              <t>All JSPROP properties in a calendar component together form a <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="1.4.9" sectionFormat="parens">PatchObject</xref>: the JSPTR parameter of a JSPROP property corresponds to a key in the PatchObject, the property value corresponds to the JSON value for that key. When converting from iCalendar to JSCalendar, the PatchObject <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> only be applied after all other iCalendar elements of the component have been converted.  Only new properties are allowed to be set, a JSON pointer in the PatchObject that points to an existing property <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be ignored.</t>
            </dd>
            <dt>Format Definition:</dt>
            <dd>
              <t>This property is defined by the following notation:</t>
              <sourcecode type="abnf"><![CDATA[
jsprop = "JSPROP" jsprop-param ":" TEXT CRLF

jsprop-param  = *(
          ; The following are MANDATORY and MUST NOT
          ; occur more than once
          ( ";" jsptr-param )
          ;
          ; The following is OPTIONAL
          ; and MAY occur more than once.
          ;
          (";" other-param)
          ;
          )
]]></sourcecode>
            </dd>
            <dt anchor="ical-prop-jsprop-examples">Example(s):</dt>
            <dd>
              <t>The following example illustrates how to convert a JSPROP property with a JSON boolean value</t>
              <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-jsprop-boolean">
                <name>Converting the JSPROP property with a JSON boolean value</name>
                <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
JSPROP;JSPTR="example.com:foo":true
]]></sourcecode>
                <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"example.com:foo": true
]]></sourcecode>
              </figure>
              <t>The following example illustrates how to convert a JSPROP property with a JSON object value</t>
              <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-jsprop-object">
                <name>Converting the JSPROP property with a JSON object value</name>
                <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
JSPROP;JSPTR="example.com:foo":{"bar":1234\,"baz":"bam"}
]]></sourcecode>
                <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"example.com:foo": {
  "bar": 1234,
  "baz": "bam"
}
]]></sourcecode>
              </figure>
              <t>The following example illustrates how to convert a JSPROP property that points to a property within a JSCalendar Alert. The JSON pointer in the JSPTR parameter is relative to the Alert object.</t>
              <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-jsprop-alert">
                <name>Converting the JSPROP property within a VALARM component</name>
                <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
...
BEGIN:VALARM
JSPROP;JSPTR="example.com:foo":"bar"
...
END:VALARM
]]></sourcecode>
                <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"@type": "Event",
"alerts": {
  "a1": {
    "@type": "Alert",
    "example.com:foo": "bar",
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
              </figure>
              <t>The following example illustrates how to convert a JSPROP property that points to a property within a JSCalendar Link. The JSON pointer in the JSPTR parameter is relative to the Event object because the Link object converts to an iCalendar property. The <xref target="ical-param-jsid">JSID parameter</xref> on the ATTACH property ensures that the JSON path remains valid during conversion.</t>
              <figure anchor="test-ical-prop-jsprop-valarm">
                <name>Converting the JSPROP property within a VALARM component</name>
                <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
...
ATTACH;JSID=mylink1:https://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc8984.html
JSPROP;JSPTR="links/mylink1/example.com:foo":"bar"
...
]]></sourcecode>
                <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"@type": "Event",
"links": {
  "mylink1": {
    "@type": "Link",
    "example.com:foo": "bar",
    "...": ""
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
              </figure>
            </dd>
          </dl>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section anchor="new-icalendar-parameters">
        <name>New Parameters</name>
        <section anchor="ical-param-jsid">
          <name>JSID</name>
          <dl newline="true">
            <dt>Parameter Name:</dt>
            <dd>JSID</dd>
            <dt>Format Definition:</dt>
            <dd>
              <sourcecode type="abnf"><![CDATA[
jsid-param  = "JSID" "=" param-value
]]></sourcecode>
            </dd>
            <dt>Description:</dt>
            <dd>
              <t>This parameter specifies the JSON object key of the JSCalendar object to which an iCalendar property converts to. For example, this parameter set on an ATTACH property within a VEVENT component defines the key of the Link object value in the Event object's "links" property (see below for an example).</t>
              <t>The value of the JSID parameter <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be a valid key according to the definition of the JSCalendar property to which the property that this parameter is set on converts to. Typically, this requires the value to be a valid <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="1.4.1" sectionFormat="parens">Id</xref>.</t>
            </dd>
            <dt>Example(s):</dt>
            <dd>
              <figure anchor="test-ical-param-jsid-attach">
                <name>Converting the JSID parameter on an ATTACH property</name>
                <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
ATTACH;JSID=mylink1:https://example.com
]]></sourcecode>
                <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"links": {
  "mylink1": {
    "@type": "Link",
    "href": "https://example.com"
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
              </figure>
            </dd>
          </dl>
        </section>
        <section anchor="ical-param-jsptr">
          <name>JSPTR</name>
          <dl newline="true">
            <dt>Parameter Name:</dt>
            <dd>JSPTR</dd>
            <dt>Format Definition:</dt>
            <dd>
              <sourcecode type="abnf"><![CDATA[
jsptr-param  = "JSPTR" "=" quoted-string
]]></sourcecode>
            </dd>
            <dt>Description:</dt>
            <dd>This parameter is specified on a <xref target="ical-prop-jsprop">JSPROP</xref> property.  Its value is a JSON pointer <xref target="RFC6901"/> that points to a JSCalendar property.
        </dd>
            <dt>Description:</dt>
            <dd>
              <t>This parameter has a single value that <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be a valid JSON pointer as defined in <xref target="RFC6901"/>. The value <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be quoted to preserve its case-sensitivity and it <bcp14>MUST NOT</bcp14> contain the DQUOTE character. See <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2"/> for how to format parameter values.</t>
            </dd>
            <dt>Example(s):</dt>
            <dd>
              <sourcecode type="text/plain"><![CDATA[
JSPROP;JSPTR="example.com:foo":"bar"
]]></sourcecode>
              <t>For further examples, see <xref target="ical-prop-jsprop-examples"/>.</t>
            </dd>
          </dl>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section anchor="updates-jscalendar">
      <name>Updates to JSCalendar</name>
      <section anchor="new-jscalendar-properties">
        <name>New Properties</name>
        <section anchor="jscal-prop-icalcomponent">
          <name>iCalComponent</name>
          <dl newline="true">
            <dt>Name:</dt>
            <dd>iCalComponent</dd>
            <dt>Context:</dt>
            <dd>Any JSCalendar object</dd>
            <dt>Type:</dt>
            <dd><tt>ICalComponent</tt> (optional)</dd>
            <dt>Description</dt>
            <dd>
              <t>This contains information about an iCalendar component that got converted to JSCalendar.  It allows for preserving the name of the iCalendar component and some or all of its properties and subcomponents.</t>
              <t>An ICalComponent object has the following properties:</t>
              <dl>
                <dt>@type: String (mandatory)</dt>
                <dd>This specifies the type of this object. This <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be ICalComponent.</dd>
                <dt>name: String (mandatory)</dt>
                <dd>This is the name of the iCalendar component in lowercase.</dd>
                <dt>components: *[][] (optional)</dt>
                <dd>This contains subcomponents of the iCalendar component which did not convert to standard JSCalendar elements. The value <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be a list of iCalendar components formatted in jCal as defined in <xref target="RFC7265" section="3.3" sectionFormat="of"/>.
                </dd>
                <dt>convertedProperties: String[ICalProperty] (optional)</dt>
                <dd>
                  <t>This contains conversion-related information about the component's properties that got partially or fully converted to JSCalendar.  Each key defines the path to a property of the JSCalendar object on which the "iCalComponent" property is set on.  The value for each key contains information about the "iCalendar" property which converted to the "object" property located at that key (see <xref target="jscal-prop-icalproperty"/>).</t>
                  <t>The key <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be a valid key of a PatchObject as defined in <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="1.4.9" sectionFormat="of"/>.  The key <bcp14>MUST NOT</bcp14> point into a nested property, unless there is no way to otherwise preserve the "iCalendar" property elements. For example, if a VEVENT contains an ATTENDEE property, then any iCalendar information about the ATTENDEE property <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be set in the "iCalProperty" property of the converted Participant object (see <xref target="ical-prop-attendee"/>).  In contrast, information about a RDATE property contained in a VEVENT would be located by a key pointing into the <tt>recurrenceOverrides</tt> property of the Event object (see <xref target="ical-prop-rdate"/>).</t>
                </dd>
                <dt>properties: *[][] (optional)</dt>
                <dd>This contains properties of the iCalendar component which did not convert to standard JSCalendar elements. The value <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be a list of iCalendar properties formatted in jCal as defined in <xref target="RFC7265" section="3.4" sectionFormat="of"/>.
              </dd>
              </dl>
            </dd>
          </dl>
          <t>The example in <xref target="test-jscal-prop-icalcomponent"/> describes how to convert unknown iCalendar elements to the "iCalComponent" property. The "X-FOO" parameter set on the SUMMARY property illustrates how to preserve an unknown iCalendar parameter on a property that does convert to a standard JSCalendar element. The "X-BAR" property and "X-BAZ" component illustrate how to convert entirely unknown iCalendar elements.</t>
          <figure anchor="test-jscal-prop-icalcomponent">
            <name>Converting unknown iCalendar elements to the iCalComponent property</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
BEGIN:VEVENT
SUMMARY;X-FOO=bar:test
...
X-BAR:bam
...
BEGIN:X-BAZ
UID:507A08F9-81D8-4D16-9480-D6D75E977943
END:X-BAZ
...
]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
{
  "@type": "Event",
  "title": "test",
  "iCalComponent": {
    "@type": "ICalComponent",
    "name": "vevent",
    "convertedProperties": {
      "title": {
        "@type": "ICalProperty",
        "name": "summary",
        "parameters": {
          "x-foo": "bar"
        }
      }
    },
    "properties": [
      [
        "x-bar",
        {},
        "unknown",
        "bam"
      ]
    ],
    "components": [
      [
        "x-baz",
        [
          [
            "uid",
            {},
            "text",
            "507A08F9-81D8-4D16-9480-D6D75E977943"
          ]
        ],
        []
      ]
    ]
  },
  "...": ""
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
        <section anchor="jscal-prop-icalproperty">
          <name>iCalProperty</name>
          <dl newline="true">
            <dt>Name:</dt>
            <dd>iCalProperty</dd>
            <dt>Context:</dt>
            <dd>Any JSCalendar object</dd>
            <dt>Type:</dt>
            <dd><tt>ICalProperty</tt> (optional)</dd>
            <dt>Description:</dt>
            <dd>
              <t>This contains conversion-related information about an iCalendar property that got partially or fully converted to a JSCalendar object.  It allows for preserving the name of the "iCalendar" property and some or all of its parameters.</t>
              <t>An ICalProperty object has the following properties:</t>
              <dl>
                <dt>@type: String (mandatory)</dt>
                <dd>This specifies the type of this object. This <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> be ICalProperty.</dd>
                <dt>name: String (mandatory)</dt>
                <dd>This is the name of the "iCalendar" property in lowercase.</dd>
                <dt>valueType: String (optional)</dt>
                <dd>This is the name of the "iCalendar" property value type in lowercase.</dd>
                <dt>parameters: String[String] (optional)</dt>
                <dd>This contains parameters of the "iCalendar" property. The value <bcp14>MUST</bcp14> comply with iCalendar parameters formatted in jCal as defined in <xref target="RFC7265" section="3.5" sectionFormat="of"/>.</dd>
              </dl>
            </dd>
          </dl>
          <t>The example in <xref target="test-jscal-prop-icalproperty"/> describes how to convert an unknown parameter to the "iCalProperty" property. The ATTACH property converts to a Link object. To preserve the unknown "X-FOO" parameter, the "iCalProperty" property is set on the Link object.</t>
          <figure anchor="test-jscal-prop-icalproperty">
            <name>Converting the ATTACH property with an unknown parameter</name>
            <sourcecode type="text/calendar"><![CDATA[
ATTACH;X-FOO=bar:https://example.com/example.jpg
  ]]></sourcecode>
            <sourcecode type="json"><![CDATA[
"links": {
  "l1": {
    "@type": "Link",
    "href": "https://example.com/example.jpg",
    "iCalProperty": {
      "@type": "ICalProperty",
      "name": "attach",
      "parameters": {
        "x-foo": "bar"
      }
    }
  }
}
]]></sourcecode>
          </figure>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section anchor="IANA">
      <!-- All drafts are required to have an IANA considerations section.  See RFC 8126 for a guide.-->
      <name>IANA Considerations</name>
    </section>
  </middle>
  <back>
    <references>
      <name>References</name>
      <references>
        <name>Normative References</name>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2119.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2397.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.5234.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.5545.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.5870.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.6047.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.6638.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.6838.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.6901.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.7265.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.7529.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.7953.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.7986.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.8174.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.8259.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.8288.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.8607.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.9073.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.9074.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://xml2rfc.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.9253.xml"/>
        <reference anchor="TZDB" target="https://www.iana.org/time-zones">
          <front>
            <title>IANA Time Zone Database</title>
            <author/>
            <date/>
          </front>
        </reference>
      </references>
      <references>
        <name>Informative References</name>
        <!--[I-D.calconnect-vobject-i18n] IESG state Expired. Entered the long way to get the correct initials-->
        <reference anchor="jmap-calendars" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-jmap-calendars/">
          <front>
            <title>JMAP for Calendars</title>
            <author fullname="Neil Jenkins" initials="N.M." surname="Jenkins">
              <organization>Fastmail</organization>
            </author>
            <author fullname="Michael Douglass" initials="M." surname="Douglass">
              <organization>Spherical Cow Group</organization>
            </author>
            <date day="22" month="July" year="2024"/>
          </front>
          <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-jmap-calendars"/>
        </reference>
        <reference anchor="ical-tasks" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-calext-ical-tasks">
          <front>
            <title>Task Extensions to iCalendar</title>
            <author fullname="Michael Douglass" initials="M." surname="Douglass">
              <organization>Bedework Commercial Services</organization>
            </author>
            <author fullname="Adrian Apthorp" initials="A." surname="Apthorp">
              <organization>DHL Express</organization>
            </author>
            <date day="30" month="July" year="2024"/>
          </front>
          <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-calext-ical-tasks"/>
        </reference>
        <reference anchor="jscalendarbis" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-ietf-calext-jscalendarbis/">
          <front>
            <title>JSCalendar: A JSON Representation of Calendar Data</title>
            <author fullname="Neil Jenkins" initials="N.M." surname="Jenkins">
              <organization>Fastmail</organization>
            </author>
            <author fullname="Robert Stepanek" initials="R." surname="Stepanek">
              <organization>Fastmail</organization>
            </author>
            <date day="13" month="May" year="2025"/>
          </front>
          <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-calext-jscalendarbis"/>
        </reference>
        <reference anchor="icaljscalexts" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-stepanek-icalendar-jscalendar-extensions/">
          <front>
            <title>iCalendar Format Extensions for JSCalendar</title>
            <author fullname="Robert Stepanek" initials="R." surname="Stepanek">
              <organization>Fastmail</organization>
            </author>
            <date day="13" month="May" year="2025"/>
          </front>
          <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-stepanek-icalendar-jscalendar-extensions"/>
        </reference>
      </references>
    </references>
    <section anchor="appendix-discrepancies">
      <name>Discrepancies between iCalendar and JSCalendar</name>
      <t>This section highlights iCalendar and JSCalendar elements for which no conversion rule to a standard element is defined in this document. This is informational and only complete at the time of publication of this document.</t>
      <t>Implementations <bcp14>MAY</bcp14> choose to convert the following elements, for example using the properties defined in <xref target="updates-icalendar"/> and <xref target="updates-jscalendar"/>, or they might convert them to some vendor-specific extension properties. Later RFC documents might also define new standard elements and register them at IANA, either extending this list of inconvertible elements, or rather reduce it by introducing a standard element to convert to.</t>
      <section>
        <name>Unsupported iCalendar Elements</name>
        <section>
          <name>Components</name>
          <t>The following components do not convert to a standard element in JSCalendar:</t>
          <ul>
            <li>
              <xref target="RFC7953" section="3.1" sectionFormat="comma">AVAILABLE</xref>
            </li>
            <li>
              <xref target="RFC7953" section="3.1" sectionFormat="comma">VAVAILABILITY</xref>
            </li>
            <li>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.6.4" sectionFormat="comma">VFREEBUSY</xref>
            </li>
            <li>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.6.3" sectionFormat="comma">VJOURNAL</xref>
            </li>
            <li>
              <xref target="RFC9073" section="7.3" sectionFormat="comma">VRESOURCE</xref>
            </li>
            <li>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.6.5" sectionFormat="comma">VTIMEZONE</xref>
            </li>
            <li>
              <xref target="ical-tasks" section="14.1" sectionFormat="comma">VSTATUS</xref>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </section>
        <section>
          <name>Properties by Component</name>
          <t>The following components are defined to contain the listed properties. But these properties do not convert to a standard JSCalendar element.</t>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC9073" section="7.1" sectionFormat="comma">PARTICIPANT</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.2" sectionFormat="comma">CATEGORIES</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.4" sectionFormat="comma">COMMENT</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.2" sectionFormat="comma">CONTACT</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.7.1" sectionFormat="comma">CREATED</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.7.3" sectionFormat="comma">LAST-MODIFIED</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC9253" section="8.2" sectionFormat="comma">LINK</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.7" sectionFormat="comma">LOCATION</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC9073" section="6.2" sectionFormat="comma">PARTICIPANT-TYPE</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.9" sectionFormat="comma">PRIORITY</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="ical-tasks" section="12.2" sectionFormat="comma">REASON</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.5" sectionFormat="comma">RELATED-TO</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.8.3" sectionFormat="comma">REQUEST-STATUS</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.10" sectionFormat="comma">RESOURCES</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.11" sectionFormat="comma">STATUS</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC9074" section="6.6" sectionFormat="comma">STRUCTURED-DATA</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.7" sectionFormat="comma">UID</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.6" sectionFormat="comma">URL</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.6.6" sectionFormat="comma">VALARM</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.1" sectionFormat="comma">ATTACH</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.1" sectionFormat="comma">ATTENDEE</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.5" sectionFormat="comma">DESCRIPTION</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.2.5" sectionFormat="comma">DURATION</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC9074" section="8.1" sectionFormat="comma">PROXIMITY</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.6.2" sectionFormat="comma">REPEAT</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC9073" section="6.5" sectionFormat="comma">STYLED-DESCRIPTION</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.12" sectionFormat="comma">SUMMARY</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.7" sectionFormat="comma">UID</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.4" sectionFormat="comma">VCALENDAR</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.7.1" sectionFormat="comma">CALSCALE</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC9253" section="8.2" sectionFormat="comma">LINK</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.7" sectionFormat="comma">REFRESH-INTERVAL</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.6" sectionFormat="comma">URL</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.7.4" sectionFormat="comma">VERSION</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.6.1" sectionFormat="comma">VEVENT</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.4" sectionFormat="comma">COMMENT</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.2" sectionFormat="comma">CONTACT</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC9253" section="8.2" sectionFormat="comma">LINK</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC9253" section="8.3" sectionFormat="comma">REFID</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.8.3" sectionFormat="comma">REQUEST-STATUS</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.10" sectionFormat="comma">RESOURCES</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC9074" section="6.6" sectionFormat="comma">STRUCTURED-DATA</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.6" sectionFormat="comma">URL</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC9073" section="7.2" sectionFormat="comma">VLOCATION</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC9253" section="8.2" sectionFormat="comma">LINK</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.7" sectionFormat="comma">UID</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC9074" section="6.6" sectionFormat="comma">STRUCTURED-DATA</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.6.2" sectionFormat="comma">VTODO</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.4" sectionFormat="comma">COMMENT</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.2.1" sectionFormat="comma">COMPLETED</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.2" sectionFormat="comma">CONTACT</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC9253" section="8.2" sectionFormat="comma">LINK</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC9253" section="8.3" sectionFormat="comma">REFID</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.8.3" sectionFormat="comma">REQUEST-STATUS</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.10" sectionFormat="comma">RESOURCES</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC9074" section="6.6" sectionFormat="comma">STRUCTURED-DATA</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="ical-tasks" section="12.4" sectionFormat="comma">TASK-MODE</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.6" sectionFormat="comma">URL</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
        </section>
        <section>
          <name>Subcomponents by Component</name>
          <t>The following components are defined to contain the listed subcomponents. But these subcomponents do not convert to a standard JSCalendar element.</t>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC9073" section="7.1" sectionFormat="comma">PARTICIPANT</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC9073" section="7.2" sectionFormat="comma">VLOCATION</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
        </section>
        <section>
          <name>Properties by Value Type</name>
          <t>The following properties convert to a standard JSCalendar element for some other value type, but they do not for the listed value types.</t>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.5.2" sectionFormat="comma">RDATE</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.3.9" sectionFormat="comma">PERIOD</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
        </section>
        <section>
          <name>Parameters by Property</name>
          <t>The following properties are defined to contain the listed parameters. But these parameters do not convert to a standard JSCalendar element.</t>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.1" sectionFormat="comma">ATTACH</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC8607" section="4.2" sectionFormat="comma">FILENAME</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC8607" section="4.3" sectionFormat="comma">MANAGED-ID</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.1" sectionFormat="comma">ATTENDEE</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.6" sectionFormat="comma">DIR</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC6638" section="7.1" sectionFormat="comma">SCHEDULE-AGENT</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC6638" section="7.2" sectionFormat="comma">SCHEDULE-FORCE-SEND</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC6638" section="7.3" sectionFormat="comma">SCHEDULE-STATUS</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.18" sectionFormat="comma">SENT-BY</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.10" sectionFormat="comma">LANGUAGE</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.2" sectionFormat="comma">CATEGORIES</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.10" sectionFormat="comma">LANGUAGE</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.11" sectionFormat="comma">CONFERENCE</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.10" sectionFormat="comma">LANGUAGE</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.5" sectionFormat="comma">DESCRIPTION</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.1" sectionFormat="comma">ALTREP</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.10" sectionFormat="comma">IMAGE</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.1" sectionFormat="comma">ALTREP</xref>
              </li>
              <li><xref target="RFC7986" section="6.1" sectionFormat="comma">DISPLAY</xref> (if the parameter value contains more than one "displayval").
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC9253" section="8.2" sectionFormat="comma">LINK</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.10" sectionFormat="comma">LANGUAGE</xref>
              </li>
              <li><xref target="RFC9253" section="6.1" sectionFormat="comma">LINKREL</xref> (if the parameter value does not conform to the "reg-rel-type" ABNF in <xref target="RFC8288" section="3.3" sectionFormat="comma"/>).
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.7" sectionFormat="comma">LOCATION</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.1" sectionFormat="comma">ALTREP</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.10" sectionFormat="comma">LANGUAGE</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC7986" section="5.1" sectionFormat="comma">NAME</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.1" sectionFormat="comma">ALTREP</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.3" sectionFormat="comma">ORGANIZER</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.18" sectionFormat="comma">SENT-BY</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.10" sectionFormat="comma">LANGUAGE</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC6638" section="7.1" sectionFormat="comma">SCHEDULE-AGENT</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC6638" section="7.2" sectionFormat="comma">SCHEDULE-FORCE-SEND</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC6638" section="7.3" sectionFormat="comma">SCHEDULE-STATUS</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.4" sectionFormat="comma">RECURRENCE-ID</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.13" sectionFormat="comma">RANGE</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.4.5" sectionFormat="comma">RELATED-TO</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC9253" section="6.2" sectionFormat="comma">GAP</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.8.3" sectionFormat="comma">REQUEST-STATUS</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.10" sectionFormat="comma">LANGUAGE</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.10" sectionFormat="comma">RESOURCES</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.1" sectionFormat="comma">ALTREP</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.10" sectionFormat="comma">LANGUAGE</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC9073" section="6.5" sectionFormat="comma">STYLED-DESCRIPTION</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.1" sectionFormat="comma">ALTREP</xref>
              </li>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC9073" section="5.3" sectionFormat="comma">DERIVED</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.1.12" sectionFormat="comma">SUMMARY</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.1" sectionFormat="comma">ALTREP</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
          <section>
            <name>
              <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.8.3.2" sectionFormat="comma">TZNAME</xref>
            </name>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <xref target="RFC5545" section="3.2.10" sectionFormat="comma">LANGUAGE</xref>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section>
        <name>Unsupported JSCalendar Properties</name>
        <t>The following properties are defined for the respective object type, but they do not convert to a standard iCalendar element.</t>
        <section>
          <name>
            <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4" sectionFormat="comma">Event and Task</xref>
          </name>
          <ul>
            <li>
              <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.6.1" sectionFormat="comma">localizations</xref>
            </li>
            <li>
              <xref target="jscalendarbis" section="4.2.4" sectionFormat="comma">showWithoutTime</xref>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </back>
</rfc>
